<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Pokhara Tourism Council</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="phewa">
        \n\nPhewa Tal ‘lake’ is the biggest lake which is the central attraction in Pokhara. You can walk along its edge or hire a boat (sail boat or paddle boat) and move around the Lakeside. It takes a day to explore the distant shores, villages, aquatic and bird life and to watch local fisherman collecting the day’s catch. Don’t miss the stunning reflection of the snow-capped Annapurna in the calm water of Phewa early in the morning.</string>

        <string name="phewa1">
\n\nThe surface area of the lake is about 4.43 sq. km., and the maximum and average depth of the lake is 12.3 m and 11.71 m. respectively. The lake has about 51.9 million cubic meters average volume of water. The best way to experience the Lakeside is to walk around the area, and is good to get moving on foot.

\n\nThere’s a myth about the formation of Phewa lake. Prior to its formation, a river Harpan Khola ‘river’ used to flow by the side of a small temple of Goddess Barahi and a village on the eastern bank of the river. It is said that one day Goddess Barahi visited the village in the form of an old woman begging door to door. The woman told the people who gave her alms that a few days later a flood would sweep away the village and that place would turn into a huge lake. As she said it rained heavily after some days for over a week and the village was swept away by the flood. At the same time the part of hill where Fishtail Lodge stands at present slipped down and blocked the river then the lake formed.
    </string>
    <string name="begnas">
        \n\nThese two picturesque lakes are perfectly serene and clean just 15 km. away towards east from Lakeside. A trip to these lakes makes a perfect day for overnight trip from proper Pokhara. The activities like swimming, boating and fishing are possible in Begnas lake. It is surrounded by hillocks and greeneries except towards the south which is the entrance to the lake. Its area is 3.73 sq. km. with round shape. There are many guest houses at the western shore of the lake from where one can have undisturbed views of the lake and the Himalayas. To get there, you should take the last left before the bridge at Begnas Chowk ‘junction’ which passes the fisheries.</string>
<string name="begnas1">
\n\nFollow the road straight through Begnas Chowk ‘junction’, which climbs up the hill and reveals the isolated beauty of Rupa Tal ‘lake’ downward to the right hand side. After passing through a small village on top of the hill, where there is a luxury eco resort, take the next left down the road walk a few hundred meters to reach the Rupa lake. Rupa is extended from east to west with narrow width. Its total area is 1,15sq. km. and the shape looks like a serpent.

\n\nIt is said that this lake looks like a lizard, changing its color from red, blue, green to other different colors. People say that there are many medicinal plants in the vicinity. One can have a very clear view of the mountain ranges from the hillock which separates the two lakes: Begnas and Rupa. While visiting Rupa one can also have an opportunity to observe the Fishery Research Center.
    </string>
    <string name="Seti">
        \n\nThis is another 7 km. long fascinating sight in Pokhara which begins from K.I. Sing Bridge to Dhungesanghu with openings at Tulsighat and Ramghat. The snow fed Seti river flows along a series of gorges through the heart of Pokhara. Its murmer can be heard and foaming water can be viewed from a bridge near British Camp, Narayansthan Bridge, Mahendra Bridge and Prithivi Highway Bridge near the Pokhara stadium. The river flowing more than 47 meter below the bridges struggling its way through an incredibly narrow canyon gives a thrilling sensation. One can easily and/or clearly observe the turbulent flow of water while watching from the bridge. On the left hand side, while crossing the new bridge, towards Gurkha Memorial Museum, there is the old K.I. Sing Bridge made of cement and concrete. It is the first concrete bridge constructed in Pokhara.
    </string>
    <string name="bhim">
        \n\nThere is a huge ingenious granite black rock like a big globe of about 8 m. height and circumference of 26 m. The stone lies in P.N. Campus complex in Pokhara. This round rock is named as Bhim Dhunga. This is the biggest rock in Pokhara valley. </string>
    <string name="bhim1">
    \n\nBhima is one of the brothers of Pancha Pandava ‘five pandavas’ mentioned in Hindu mythology belonging about 1500 BC. According to the myth as narrated by the local people, the rock was thrown as a shot-put by Bhima, physically the mightiest brother of pandavas, from Bhimad. So it has its name as Bhim Dhunga. Dhunga in Nepali means ‘rock’ or ‘stone’. Local people have established a deity called Kali on the same spot. So it is also called Bhim Kali. Actually, the geographical legacy is that this huge rock has been carried down from the vicinity mountain during glacial period by moving glacier. Mr. Krishna Prasad Poudel, a geographer opines that the very Bhim Dhunga with round shape might have been rolled down by catastrophic outburst.
    </string>
    <string name="mahendra">
        \n\nThis is a large limestone cave famous for its stalactites and stalagmites, located 9 km. to the north-east from Lakeside. This place was first explored by British expedition team in 1978 and then explored again by Daniel Gebuer in 1980. The length of the cave is 215 meter long and is stretched over 50 ropanies of land. The width of the entrance is 16 meters whereas in the center it is only 3.5 meter wide. In the beginning, this cave was called Bat Cave by the local people. Later on, it was named after the name of the then king Mahendra after his visit to the cave in 1960.
    </string>
    <string name="bat">
        \n\nWith its name as Chamere Gupha in Nepali, Bats’ cave is the popular name in English. This cave is located half kilometer west from Mahendra cave. It is still a popular and adventurous cave to get into. The natural environment of this cave has attracted thousands of bats as they feel no disturbance inside. People usually enter inside the cave carrying a torch light with a sense of adventure.
    </string>
     <string name="bat1">
        \n\nThe visitors must be cautious, since the cave is not yet equipped with electricity and the path is also full of sharp stones. The water dripping from the ceiling makes the path wet and slippery. One can hear haunted sound inside the cave even from the entrance. The area of the Bats’ Cave is 10 m. depth and 6 m. height along with its 135 m. length. There is a small stream flowing deep under the rock. At the far end of the cave there is a small narrow hole. However, the cave at its center is amazingly spacious. There are large boulders cut out of solid rock inside the cave. Standing on the boulder you can look around the cave. In the middle of it you can see hundreds of bats hanging on the ceiling. Walking through the darkness in the light of a torch, and finding the exit of the cave is indeed a tough and adventurous task. If one is not courageous enough, better not to enter the cave.
    </string>
    <string name="gupt">
        \n\nIt is located 3 km. to the south west from Lakeside near Devi’s fall. It is believed to be five hundred year old and was discovered in 1992. The cave is a popular pilgrimage site. There is a natural image of Lord Shiva, which was naturally found beneath the earth. Well-maintained steps are constructed with the provision of sufficient light to enter the cave. This cave is one of the outlets of Devi’s fall. There is a small tunnel behind the image of Shiva that links the cave to the Devi’s fall. It takes about 10 minutes to reach Devi’s fall through the tunnel. Visitors to this cave have the opportunity to enjoy the underground view of the Devi’s fall.
    </string>
    <string name="devi">
        \n\nDevi’s Fall is a fascinating waterfall located 2 km. southwest from Lakeside on the Siddhartha high way towards Syangja. The fall exists because the over flow or excess water of Phewa Lake is drained out through a hole and water runs underground to a distance of about one kilometer down which mingles with a rivulet called Phusre khola ‘rivulet’. The hole is about 29 feet in diameter and 50 feet deep. A big flow of water speedily flowing down into the mouth of the cave exposes lovely rainbows flickering unsteady into the water vapor. Then the big mass of water flows invisibly and vanishes below the hole which provides extremely exciting and pleasant feelings. The local name for the waterfall is Patale Chhango.
</string>
      <string name="devi1">



\n\nThe name Patale Chhango in Nepali has become popular among the tourists and tourism operators as ‘Devi’s fall’, after a miserable death of a Swiss lady by slipping in the water fall.

\n\nIn 1961, Swiss couples were having a bath immediately above the waterfall with their dog. Around 2 Pm, when the water gates of the Phewa Dam were opened as usual, overflow of the rushing lake water approached them. It is said that their dog saw the rushing flood from the distance and barked loudly. However, the couple could not pay any attention to the mere sound of the dog. In a twinkling of an eye, the rushing water approached them and swept away the lady down into the hole. However, her husband survived.
    </string>
    <string name="mount">
        \n\nPokhara is the only place in the world from where you can wonder 8000 m. high peaks staying below 1000 m. from sea level. Mt. Machhapuchhre (Fishtail) is one of the most prominent peaks. It is regarded as a holy mountain, and therefore, it is forbidden to be climbed. Two of the world’s 14 highest mountains, Dhaulagiri and Annapurna can be seen from various parts of Pokhara city. This is not enough, we can view the whole range of mountains from Dhaulagiri to Manaslu in a glance if we just make a half an hour hike from Pokhara to any hilltops.
    </string>
    <string name="kaski">
       \n\n Kaski was the ancestral state of the Shah Kings of Nepal and Kaskikot was the capital of Kaski since 1650 years ago. It lies 16 km. to the north from Lakeside. This hilltop is easily accessible by any type of vehicle or on foot. It is such a nice destination that Pokhara valley, green forest with beautiful landscapes, gorgeous and sky scraper snow capped mountains and lakes are clearly visible from this hilltop. Kaskikot can be one-day visit tour or more from Pokhara. It deserves the capacity to welcome the visitors.


    </string>
    <string name="sarang">
        \n\nThis, 1,592 m. high mountain, located on the northern side of Phewa Tal, is one of the most popular destinations for its breathtaking panoramic views of the Annapurna and Dhaulagiri ranges, the Pokhara valley and Phewa Tal. Enjoying the sunrise and sunset from this former Kaski fort is an experience not to be missed when visiting Pokhara. It is also a thrill to watch tandem and solo paraglide taking off daily just below the top. Walking up the stone steps from the north end of Lakeside (Sedi) takes 2 -3 hours, while taxis can take you up just below the summit. A day trip on a motorbike is a fun way to explore the mountain, its local villages all the way along the ridge top to Naudanda or down to Pame at the end of the Phewa Lake.
</string>
     <string name="sarang2">
\n\nThe word sarang means a traditional dance related to fighting and war. In such dance, men dance with sword in their hand by beating a drum. In Sarangkot, military guards used to live during the period of Shah kings who had their palace in Kaskikot. The militaries in Sarangkot used to visit Kaskikot every day for sarang dance, and returned to Sarangkot every morning. Thus, the place, later on, is known as Sarangkot. It’s very windy place which provides cool and exciting experience.
    </string>
    <string name="aus">
        \n\nAustrian Camp which is previously known as Thulakharka, offers striking views over the valleys and stunning views of the Annapurna Mountain range including the views of sunrise and sunset. It is an easy trek in the foothill of Annapurna near Pokhara This trip can be done all year round and is also very suitable for people without any hiking experience and people of all ages. Thulakharka is supposed one of the best place in the world to observe and counting the migratory hunting birds which happens from the first week of September till mid December.
</string>
    <string name="aus1">
\n\nDuration : 2-3 days
\n\nDifficulty : Easy
\n\nMax Elevation : 2100m
\n\nStart : Kande / Milanchowk
    </string>
    <string name="thul">
        \n\nWith an elevation of 1450 m., located 17 km. north-east from Lakeside, is a perfect hill station to view the Phewa and Kamal Tal ‘lake’ of Pokhara and Begnas, Maidi, Dipang, Gude, Nureni and Khaste lakes of Lekhnath including the view of all the ranges of mountain from Dhaulagiri to Manaslu. Thulakot also carries a historic importance as it was one of the Chaubise (twenty-four) kingdoms of Kaski. One should look for a good weather before coming to this place as this place would look heavenly on a clear/sunny day when you can see the mountains so close that you might think you could reach there in a day. Thulakot is accessible by any means of transport, and there is regular service of local buses to this spot from Pokhara city.
    </string>
    <string name="matti">
        \n\nThis is an excellent hill station, from where all the mountain ranges, beautiful landscapes, in full range of Pokhara valley and more than 8 districts can be seen in clear weather. The hill station is situated at an elevation of 1540m from Sea level and 11km south west from Lakeside Pokhara .The hill station is also equipped with a beautiful view tower and home stay facilities.
    </string>
    <string name="foksing">
        \n\nIt is a hill station about 4 km. south of Pokhara airport with an elevation of 1082 m. from the sea level. It is a beautiful ridge, rich especially in topographical point of view. The view of the whole Pokhara valley, its lakes and surroundings, evergreen hills with the background of full Annapurna mountain range is so lovely and worth seeing from this hill that could be hardly taken from any place on the earth. Observing the scenes in the morning and at moon-lit night is even more pleasant and alluring. Watching take off and landing aircraft at Pokhara airport is additional most pleasant scene from this hill station.
    </string>
    <string name="kahun">
        \n\nWith an elevation of  1400 meters, located 10 km to the east from Lakeside, Kahundanda is a joyful spot to have the panoramic view of snow capped mountains, beautiful landscapes, green hills, forests, rivers, lakes and the Pokhara Valley. One can see the forked summit of Machhapuchhre and other mountains from the hilltop.

\n\nIt is not a fort or station for military purpose. It is a religious spot (hilltop) where in the festivals like, Chaite Dashain and Bada Dashain, male animals like buffalo, sheep, goat and also the birds like pigeon, duck, rooster etc are sacrificed in the name of the goddess Durga Bhagawati.
    </string>
    <string name="pandh">
        \n\nLocated 30 km. west from Lakeside, is a historical place which gives the information about the time before the political and geographical unification of Nepal when there were 24 and 22 states in Western Nepal. There are still the ruins of a fort made of stone wall on the top of the hillock. It has 200 m. circumference about 3 m height and 1 m width. During the period of 22 and 24 states, Parbat – one of a 24 states, used to attack the adjacent state Kaski. To protect Kaski from the Parbat state, the king of Kaski had made fort on the hill of Pandhur.
    </string>
    <string name="anudh">
        \n\nWith an elevation of 1,100 m. from sea level, this hilltop is situated in the south-west side of Phewa lake. It has two special characteristics: in summer, this place remains the most cooling spot, and in winter, it receives direct sun whole day, which makes the temperature favorable in both the seasons. The visitors can view more snow capped mountains from this hilltop than any other hilltop stations of Pokhara. Besides other mountains, Hatti Sunde (elephant-trunk-shaped), Rakanoyar, Glacier Dome, Manapathi etc. can be seen/viewed from this top including Larke and Ganesh Himal. You can also have a bird’s eye view of Phewa Lake from this hilltop.

\n\nThere are 4 routes to reach to the top: first route is to hike an hour from Chhorepatan to the top, second route is to cross the Phewa Lake by boat near Barahi Temple and hike up an hour to the top, the third route is to hike 2 hours from Phewa Dam and crossing a very short suspension bridge via Raniban forest, and the fourth route starts from Kalimati of Pumdi Bhumdi, the other side of the Phewa Lake which is the shortest route to hike to Anadu hill enjoying the sceneries of village and green fields.
    </string>
    <string name="intern">
        \n\nThe International Mountain Museum, located 1.5 km. south from Pokhara airport and about 5 km. from Lakeside, is devoted to the mountains of Nepal. It provides information on mountaineering and the cultures, environments, history, geography and ecology of the Himalayas. This is truly a unique site from where three 8,000 m. high peaks – Dhaulagiri, Annapurna-I and Manaslu are visible and no place in the world offers such a panoramic view in single sight. The museum opens daily from 9 am to 5 pm.
    </string>
    <string name="region">
        \n\nThe museum reflects the ethnic mosaic – costumes, ornaments, musical instruments, and agricultural tools, hunting kits, smoking pipes, coins and manuscripts and reflects a good picture of a way of life of various ethnic groups of western Nepal.
\n\nIt is located 4 km. east from Lakeside at Nayabazar, and remains open from 10 am to 4 pm except Tuesdays and public holidays.
    </string>
    <string name="anna">
        \n\nIt is also known as natural history museum, located inside the complex of Prithivi Narayan campus. The museum is exceptional collection of butterflies, insects, birds and models of wildlife as well as samples of various precious and semi precious stones and volcanic rocks. It opens from 10 am to 5 pm except Saturdays and public holidays. This museum is managed by ACAP.
    </string>
 <string name="gurkha">
     \n\nPokhara and its surrounding places are widely known as homeland of the world famous Gurkha soldiers. The Gurkha Memorial Museum, located in the premises of the British Camp, 7 km north-east from Lakeside reminds the reminiscence of the Gurkha soldiers and their historical brave works in the battlefields of first and second world wars. It contains a good collection of used uniforms, medals, photographs and other materials used by those brave and courageous Gurkha soldiers during the first and second world wars. It opens daily 8 am to 4.30 pm.
 </string>

    <string name="barahi">
        \n\nThis is a typical small pagoda styled temple dedicated to Goddess Barahi built on a small land mass in the middle of Phewa lake. The temple is one of the most famous places of pilgrimage. The atmosphere is so tranquil that one can enjoy the green forest scenery just across the lake towards south, full-scale scenery of the lake and amazing reflection of the Annapurna and Fish-tail Mountains on the surface of the lake. There are major celebrations during Dashain, the biggest Nepali festival which usually falls in the month of October. Boats and ferries are available on rent to get to the temple.
    </string>
    <string name="kedar">
        \n\nKedareswar Temple is beautifully constructed as a replica of Pashupatinath temple in Kathmandu in the premises of Komagane Miteri Park near to Fishtail Lodge and adjacent to Phewa Lake and dedicated to Lord Shiva. The premises of the temple is full of devotees to participate in the Bol Bam Yatra (celebration) in the month of Shrawan (mid July – mid Aug) and other religious practices are performed in the temple round the whole year. The park was named in memory of official friendship relation between Pokhara city of Nepal and Komagane city of Japan. This is the right place to observe Nepali way of performing wedding ceremonies in full length.
    </string>
    <string name="Ram">
        \n\nRam Mandir ( Hindu temple ) situated near Birauta chowk just one and half km away from lakeside to the south. Ram is one of the many popular figures and deities in Hinduism and considered to be one of the most important avatars of Vishnu. he is revered for his unending compassion, courage and devotion to religious values and duty.

\n\nJust a few minutes walk to the south we can see the first hydro power station in Pokhara, which is a canal drop type power station. It has 315 steps down from the edge of the cliff to go to the power station. It is an interesting place to visit with beautiful attraction of waterfall, river, natural swimming pool, cliffs, caves, and the landscapes.
    </string>

    <string name="Binda">
        \n\nIt is another most important Hindu shrine of Pokhara, located on the top of a small hillock to the north end of the old bazaar, 6 km. away from Lakeside. The white dome structure is dedicated to the Goddess Bhagwati and worshipers come here to perform sacrifices, especially on Saturdays. It is believed to be one of the oldest temples in the valley, and on some days you may get chances to witness Hindu wedding ceremonies taking place in the premises of this temple.

\n\nThe monument of old Bazaar is located 4 km. north from Lakeside and just south beneath the famous Bindubasini temple. The monument closely resembles the Newari architecture of Kathmandu valley. It is a traditional bazaar and nowadays, a gathering place for many ethnically diverse groups of traders. This area has been protected as an old heritage site of Pokhara.
    </string>
    <string name="Bhadra">
        \n\nBhadrakali Temple and Karma Kagyu Chhonkerling Buddhist Monastery are situated in close proximity of Matepani nearby small hillock, surrounded by rich luscious forest, 7 Km north-east from Lakeside. The location is superb for viewing the mountain and the Pokhara city. It is also a proper place for bird and butterfly watching and for a half day hike too. The temple and monastery are surrounded by thick green forest which provides cool breeze while climbing up the steps. This is one of the examples of our religious and social harmony especially between Hinduism and Buddhism.
    </string>
    <string name="hari">
        \n\nSituated 10 km east from lakeside at an elevation of 1300m.on the top of Bhalam Village, this place is beautifully ornamented with Harihar (Shiva + Bishnu) and other Temples, historical cave for meditation, surrounded by many medicinal plant and trees, and most important attraction is to view the beautiful mountains and the Pokhara valley.

\n\nA short hike to the Temple from Bhalam village crossing Kalikhola suspension bridge is interesting and enjoyable.
    </string>
    <string name="world">
        \n\nSituated on the top of the hill south of Phewa Tal, the World Peace Pagoda also known as Shanti Stupa is a large Buddhist Stupa from where one can have tremendous views of the Annapurna, green hills, Phewa Tal and the Pokhara valley. The dome structure is a symbol of peace and has four gilt images of the Buddha from Japan, Sri Lanka, Thailand and Nepal facing four directions. The height of the monument is 11 m. and situated at an elevation of 2,100 m. from the sea level. It was built by Japanese Buddhist and opened in 1999. There are mainly three ways to access the stupa including by car all the way to the top however the nicest way is by crossing the lake by boat and then hiking up an hour to the hill or drive to Chhorepatan and gently climb to the top.
    </string>
    <string name="tibet">
        \n\nSince 1959, a large number of Tibetan refugees have been living in Nepal. The number has reached up to twenty thousand now. Pokhara is the main land of Tibetan settlement. Most of the Tibetan live in various settlements around Pokhara. Two small Tibetan settlements, Tashi Ling and Paljorling are located near Davi’s fall and Sabhagriha Chowk respectively. The largest another Tibetan settlement called Tashi Palikhel is at Hemja on the Baglung high way about 9 km. away from Lakeside. The colorful gompa in the center of the Tashi Palikhel settlement is the home for more than 200 monks.
    </string>
    <string name="para">
        \n\nCan you imagine sharing the same air space with the Himalayan griffin vultures and eagles as you shore up over the rivers, lakes, villages and terraced mountains all year round?

\n\nPokhara is a truly wonderful and fulfilling experience for the adventure- seekers. You can fly high up in the air can share the same air space with the Himalayan griffin vultures, eagles as you fly over the rivers, lakes, villages and terraced mountains. The mountain appear over you to your north and below you, the landscapes dotted with paddy fields and hamlets. This is why Pokhara is one of the hot spot among the 5 best destinations in the world for paragliding. There are several companies in Pokhara operating daily Tandem flights with their professional pilots.
    </string>
    <string name="ultra">
        \n\n“Leave your owes behind on earth, soar to heights bathe, the clouds reach out for the mountains and kiss the azure sky as you fly across.”

        \n\nUltra Light Flights provide a unique sightseeing experience that enables the passengers to catch a bird’s eye view of Pokhara valley along with the beauty of lakes and the Annapurna mountain range. The feature of flying in the aircraft is that there is only one passenger flying with one of the experienced pilot. This aircraft is open and you can feel chill breeze of the air and can enjoy taking beautiful photographs from the sky. The flights are operated from Pokhara airport especially from September to June.
    </string>
    <string name="mountain">
        \n\nChartered Mountain Flights from Pokhara will take you to the close spectacular view of some of the world’s tallest Himalayas in Annapurna region. Pokhara offers crystal clear sky even during the winter. It gives value in addition to the experience of trekking. Helicopter services are also available for those who wish to make it more private affair.
    </string>
    <string name="kay">
        \n\nWhether you would like to kayak in the Phewa or Begnas Lake or raft down the white waters of Seti River, Pokhara has it all. Several wild rivers run through the surrounding areas of Pokhara making the region a top rafting destination. Popular trips start from a half-day adventure of Seti River just 20 minutes from Lakeside which runs through the heart of Pokhara valley to several-day expeditions down the Kaligandaki, Trishuli, Marsyangdi and Lower Seti. The grades of the rapids vary from +2 to +5 depending on the river and the season.
    </string>
    <string name="cann">
        \n\n Pokhara has opened two Canyoning spots recently in Ghalel and in Ghachok of Kaski district. Both spots are approximately in equal distance from Pokhara about 20 km., which is about one-hour drive. The Pokhara canyoning at Ghalel is in operation where as the other at Ghachok is still. Be a part of excitement and support the local people.
    </string>
    <string name="cycling">
        \n\n Cycling is a unique experience to know in and around Pokhara and cheap way to explore it. One can pedal push your way through waterfalls, up and down treacherous slopes, lush forests and culturally heterogeneous communities and amidst centuries old monasteries and rice granaries. Biking or cycling up steep hills and through cruel mountain rivers is its other attractions. Bikes and bicycles are available on rent in several points around Lakeside but make sure the condition of the bike/bicycle before you set off.
    </string>
    <string name="golf">
        \n\nThere are two Golf courses and a driving range in Pokhara. Himalayan Golf Course is a world class Golf course, situated about 13 kilometers east from Lakeside, Pokhara. It offers an amazing golfing experience in a unique ground with 18 holes. It is popular as a Golf course in a paradise. Spectacular, stunning and unique location has made it an amazing Golf course in Asia. Besides this, Yeti Golf Course also offers unique golfing experience with its 9 hole course in the ground of Fulbari Resort.


    </string>
    <string name="zip">
        \n\nThis is an additional focus of adventure. It consists of a trolley cable mounted on a steel cable 1.8 kilometers in length; the ride descends 2000 feet vertical at an angle of 56 percent. With resulting speed of over 90 miles per hour, it makes the most extreme zip-line ride in the world.
    </string>
    <string name="Bunje">
        \n\nThe ultimate thrill of a Bungee jump can now be experienced in Pokhara. It is the first tower bungee in Nepal. It has a vertical drop of 70 m. and 3 second free fall. This is available at Hemja … km. away from Pokhara town.
    </string>
    <string name="swim">
        \n\nPokhara is blessed with sunny weather almost round the year because of subtropical climate and the effect of ozone layer. So to cool off on a sunny day it is better to go for a dip in a swimming pool or Begnas lake. Many hotels and clubs in Pokhara have private swimming pools. However, one can swim, grab a drink and chill poolside for a day by paying some fee. At Begnas lake one can swim from the shore at the east and west ends where there are several guest houses and restaurants.
    </string>
    <string name="rock">
        \n\nPokhara has mainly three places opened for rock climbing and are open for all the visitors.

\n\n1.Located closely just above Lakeside, in Methlang Village Sarangkot. It is a natural rock and provides opportunity for rock climbing lovers. It has 18 different routes, graded from 4C to 6B. The highest point is 23 m.
\n\n2.Bimalnagar, a relatively newer destination located 65 km. east from Pokhara next to the Prithivi high way provides very good rock climbing opportunity for natural rock climbers. It has more than a half dozen of 30 m. routes from where you can enjoy the view of Mt. Manaslu and the Marshyangdi river.
\n\n3.At the main entrance gate of International Mountain Museum (IMM), 23 m. tall 6 facets rock climbing wall is built for all the enthusiasts and lover of rock climbers to try it before they try in the natural mountains. IMM and NMA Annapurna Chapter organize Wall Climbing Competition every year on 5th February to mark its opening anniversary.
    </string>
    <string name="pony">
        \n\nPony trekking in Pokhara is a great way to explore the country’s rich landscapes which might otherwise maybe inaccessible. Ponies are available on hire for short excursions or full day trip depending on your requirements. Pony treks follow nearly the same routes as the natural treks and the walking paths.
    </string>
    <string name="honey">
        \n\nPlaces which are close to Pokhara like Baglung, Landruk, Siklis, and Ghanpokhara etc. are famous for adventurous and arduous honey hunting practices. Visitors must be aware of this type of hunting as published in the National Geographic Magazine of its unique and traditional hunting just by hanging on a locally made rope and slide down to the massive cliff and hunt honey. Those who like to enjoy the honey hunting can combine the trip with trekking from Pokhara.
    </string>
    <string name="hike">
        \n\nPokhara is not simply a gateway for trekking but also an extra ordinary destination for all sorts of tourists. Many hills and villages are easily accessible from Pokhara. While you stay at comfortable accommodations in Pokhara, you can enjoy village life at the same time. These villages still have unique specialties for their own cultures, traditions and rituals. There are many hills and hillocks around Pokhara like: Kahun , Sarangkot, Kaskikot, Naudanda, Australian Camp, Astam, Armalakot, Rupakot, Pachabhaiya, Thulakot, Pumdi, Mattikhan, Nirmal Pokhari, Dhampus, etc., which provide opportunity to enjoy local culture, sunrise, sunset, panoramic mountain view and many more.
    </string>
    <string name="fishing">
        \n\nThe lakes and confluence points of mountain streams and rivers are good spots for Sahar, Katale (Nepali native species of carp family), feel and catfish. The best fishing season starts from June to August every year. You can enjoy fishing using a lure, a reel and so on. Rods are also available at Lakeside.
    </string>
    <string name="Boating">
        \n\nPokhara is the place that makes your relaxing wonderful and memorable. Boating on the calm waters of Phewa Lake is the perfect place to relax and marvel at the reflection of the Annapurna and Mt. Fishtail. Colorful wooden boats are available on rent on the lake edge near Barahi Chowk ‘junction’ and other edges around the lake area. You can hire a boatman to paddle you around the lake or you can paddle yourself. You can also hire aluminum paddle boats and sail boats on Phewa Lake. The other lake Begnas near Pokhara also provides the same opportunity for boating. Boats with or without boatman are available on rent there as well.
    </string>
    <string name="vulture">
        \n\nIts’ an amazing place just 15 km to the north east from Pokhara at Ghachok, where you can see the activities of the rare bird – Vultures. Vulture does not hunt, but it uses the dead body of animals for its’ food.The specialities of this restaurant is to care the old animals untill their natural death , then for the vultures food.
    </string>
    <string name="ropani">
        \n\nNepal is also known as the country of festivals. The festivals are connected with our culture, traditions and the life styles. Rice is our major crop and main food of Nepali people. Keeping the importance of this crop in mind, the tradition of rice plantation ceremony called Ropain Mahotsav is being practiced/performed from the ancient period, like Ropai Jatra in Newari Culture.

\n\nWith the aim of promoting tourism through preserving this culture, Pokhara Tourism Council has been organizing this event in Pokhara since …. as a festive occasion. This festival invariably falls on 15th of Asadh (accordingly, usually on the 29th of June) every year. It is a Nepali tradition to celebrate this festival by eating beaten rice with curd, singing Asare geet ‘song’, planting rice and playing with and/or in the mud. To make the festival more interesting varieties of events like tourist race in mud, bullock race, fish catching competition etc. are performed.
    </string>
    <string name="street">
        \n\nClosely following the period of English New Year, Restaurant and Bar Association (REBAN) Pokhara has established a tradition to celebrate the Street Festival. This program begins from 28th December to 1st January every year. This festival has been proved to be an important event for the enhancement of tourism in Pokhara. This program is being held at Lakeside which is a tourism center in Pokhara.

\n\nIn such a dealing and performance, tourists get not only the tourism related information but a unique sort of pleasure out of those temporarily established street restaurants. In order to provide entertainment to tourists, folk dance and folk song are followed by the culture, art and costumes of various indigenous communities are displayed on the same occasion. Varieties of competition like, Boat Race, Tourist race, Tug–of–war etc are performed to make the festival more interesting.
    </string>
  <string name="phew">
     \n\nOn the occasion of Nepali New Year, Phewa Festival is organized every year from 7th April to 15th April at Basundhara Park just opposite to Fishtail Lodge. The festival offers various events and activities like cultural programs with live band, Children Park, competitions, New Year sale market, sales and exhibition of Nepali handicrafts, paintings, architectural and agricultural goods. It provides verities of Nepalese cuisine deliciously displayed on the occasion. This is also an event where a tourist can experience the way of exchanging greetings of Nepalese culture on the eve of Nepali New Year.

/n/nOn the other hand, the main streets of Lakeside are covered with varieties of restaurants and sale shops. Several items for fun and entertainment like cultural parade on the street, boat race, waiter race, tug-of-war, beer drinking competition etc. are performed.

  </string>
    <string name="trade">
        \n\nThe fair is organized every year in the month of November at Exhibition Center in Nayabazaar Pokhara. It provides ample opportunity to the small and cottage industries to promote their products. This festival runs for almost a week with significant commercial activities and cultural performances. Thousands of visitors are benefited by purchasing their household needs in reasonable price (less than in normal) and also enjoy the festival with varieties of songs, dance, comedy and tasty foods.
    </string>
    <string name="tourism">
        \n\nEvery year, 27th of September is celebrated as a World Tourism Day in Pokhara welcoming the guest by Pancha Kanya ‘five girls’ with Garland and Khada in musical environment. This day also reflects Nepali tradition, culture and hospitality to the guests. This is also considered to be an auspicious day in tourism. The guests are awarded by surprise gift of vouchers who step first, second and third in Pokhara Airport and at the Tourist Bus Park, Pokhara.
    </string>
    <string name="champ">
        \n\nNew concept of tourism has come into the forefront replacing the traditional ones in Nepal. As an adventurous game, paragliding competition has been started in Pokhara so as to familiarize the natural city of Pokhara in the world tourism market. This sport has become an alternative means of entertainment for all tourists coming to Nepal. Ever wondered, like a free flying bird up in the sky, if you could also soar high up in the air towards the pearly clouds, into the beautiful blue and experience the sensation of flying! It’s an amazing event of paragliding, closest to free flying without disturbing the nature. This will be an incredible ride into the air. To promote sports tourism in Nepal, the Paragliding Championship has been organizing since … in Pokhara and it falls every year at the end of February.
    </string>
    <string name="dashain">
        \n\nThis is the greatest national festival in Nepal celebrated by all Hindus and Mahayana Buddhists for 15 days starting from the new moon in October all over the country by setting up shrine of Durga, the goddess of power. The 10th day being the day of victory of Goddess Durga over the demon, Mahishasur is known as Vijaya Dashami (vijaya means victory and dashami means 10th day. On this occasion, the youngers have Tika and Jamara from the elders and the elders wish them good luck and prosperity in the future. On the following full moon after Vijaya Dashami a local fair is held at Phewa Lake for a couple of days. The government offices remain closed for 7 to 10 days except the emergency services.
    </string>
    <string name="tihar">
        \n\nThis is the festival of lights also known as Yama Panchaka celebrated all over Nepal. It is celebrated for 5 days worshiping the goddess of wealth and prosperity called Laxmi. It is a holy ritual in which faithful animals, like crows, dogs, cows and oxen are worshipped on the first four days. The main day of this festival is Bhai Tika, the fifth day when brothers are worshiped by the sisters for their long life and the sisters are blessed by the brothers, for their good health, happiness, protection and prosperity. This is also an important festival celebrated nearly a month after Dashain. The festival is colorful and musical with lots of fun.
    </string>
    <string name="twohte">
        \n\nTwohte is supposed to be the act of chasing the ghost or unseen enemies. It is celebrated as a festival during the month of September and March. It is a very colorful cultural festival of Gurung community. People assemble with their traditional dresses, fake weapons and equipments, and make the procession through the major parts of Pokhara city.
    </string>
    <string name="teej">
        \n\nThis is the great festival of women which generally falls in September. The ladies and girls worship Lord Shiva during this festival with fasting with a view to ensure a long and healthy life for their husband and family members. They rejoice themselves dancing and singing wearing red costumes and remains in fasting for more than 24 hours.
    </string>
    <string name="gai">
        \n\nThis is a weeklong cultural performance which begins from the next day of Rakshya Bandhana at the end of August. On the first day several teams of dancers consisting of at least 3 nymphs and 1 clown are presented in the dancing all along where they go. One of the members in a team is in the shape of a cow. It 
    </string>
 <string name="holi">
     \n\nIt is also known as the Festival of Colors which is commonly celebrated by all on the full moon of March. On this day, people are smeared with the several colors and some are even drenched in coloured water. On the other hand, the ethnic Thakali people celebrate this festival playing archery game on this occasion.
 </string>
    <string name="bhairav">
        \n\nThe Bhairav dance is one of the specialties of Pokhara. It is a group mask dance consisting of 12 dancers as gods and goddesses. It depicts a religious story of the interrelation between gods and goddesses which is displayed throughout the night in the month of December and January once in the 6 years’ interval.
Bhairav means a vigorous and dangerous form or incarnation of the Lord Shiva. This dance is believed to be performed to safeguard the community from unforeseen natural hazards.
    </string>
    <string name="laphewa">
        \n\nThis festival is performed in every 12 years by the ethnic Thakali community at Khobang and Marpha. The next performance is in November–December, 2016.
    </string>
<string name="visa">
    \n\nYou can extend your visa at the Department of Immigration, which has an office in Shahid Chowk. Visitors can stay in Nepal on a tourist visa for 150 days per year. In order to extend your visa, you need to fill an application form found online, print it, and then take it to the Immigration office. The minimum extension is for 15 days, which costs US $30. You have to pay US$ 2 for each additional day of stay. For a visa application, you need your passport, a printed application, a photocopy of your passport with latest visa, and visa fee in Nepali currency. The office opens Sunday-Friday from 10 am to 2 pm except on public holidays.

\n\nNormally, visitors can obtain a visa on arrival at Tribhuwan International Airport or at all major entry points of Nepal like Kakarvitta, Birgunj, Sunauli (Belahia), Nepalgunj, and Mahendranagar.
</string>
    <string name="permit">
        \n\nEvery trekker requires two permits to trek in Nepal. One is an Area Conservation Permit like ACAP (Annapurna Conservation Area Project) and another is a TIMS card (Trekker’s Information Management System).

\n\nYou need to submit a passport sized photograph along with the fee for the permits. The fee is as follows:

\n\nACAP and MCAP Rs 2000 /-
\n\nEverest and Langtang national park fee Rs 3000/-
\n\nBlue TIMS (for trekkers accompanied by a guide) Rs.1000/-
\n\nGreen TIMS card (for trekkers without a guide) Rs.2000/-

\n\nTrekking agencies can obtain permits for you or you can visit the Tourist Service Centre located in Damside, Pokhara.
    </string>
    <string name="climate">
        \n\nPokhara has a sub-tropical climate, with mild summers and mild winters. The Himalayas and surrounding green hills keep the temperature moderate. Winter offers a pleasant weather, especially from September to December. The temperature in Pokhara remains between 13˚c to 32˚c in summer and 6˚c to 27˚c in winter. The Monsoon in Pokhara starts from June and lasts till early September. Pokhara receives the heaviest rainfall in Nepal.
    </string>
    <string name="Money">
        \n\nThere are several banks and plenty of foreigncurrency-exchange services along Lakeside area in Pokhara. Visa cards, Master cards and ATM cards can be used at any time. There
are several 24-hour ATM card booths along Lakeside and in the city. Credit cards are accepted by most of the service providers. Withdrawing from ATMs is the easiest option as they have good rates and accept all major cards. The exchange rates for the day are quoted in the booths and are determined by the Central Bank of Nepal. Once you are out
of Pokhara, ATMs are scarce, so always take enough cash for your needs plus a little extra in case of emergency.
    </string>
    <string name="comm">
        \n\nInternet: There are several internet cafes in Lakeside along with free Wi-Fi services in most of the cafes, restaurants and hotels. Communicating with your family from Pokhara is convenient. Cyber cafes also offer ISD phone services. You can connect around the world at any time.

\n\nMobile Phones: Tourists can easily obtain Nepali SIM cards. There are two companies: NCELL and NTC. NTC has better coverage in the mountains. You need to fill out a form and provide a photocopy of your passport and visa. Balance top-ups for both companies are available anywhere in Nepal.
    </string>
    <string name="postal">
        \n\nPokhara’s main post office is located about 1.5 km west from Lakeside. Sending post-cards home is easy and reliable, as every bookshop in Lakeside sells post cards and stamps. They usually have a small mail-box outside their shop. Courier services like Sky Net and UPS are also available in Lakeside in case you need to send important documents.
    </string>
    <string name="electricity">
        \n\nNepal suffers from a shortage of electricity, so you will experience scheduled load-shedding. However, a majority of the hotels, restaurants, bars, and café will have alternative sources of electricity. the level of the electricity supply ranges from 200 to 220 volts.
    </string>
    <string name="medical">
        \n\nThere are several hospitals and nursing homes in Pokhara, many of which provide dental care and emergency services matching those in the West. Small pharmacies are available
throughout Pokhara, which sell over-thecounter and prescribed medicine and supplies. If you need dentist or doctor during your stay in Pokhara, both are available in Lakeside. There is some hospital and clinics in central Lakeside provide western standard care and remain open round-the-clock, providing emergency, outpatient and inpatient services ranging from acute emergencies to primary care for both adult and children.
    </string>
    <string name="ayurveda">
        \n\n Ayurveda is a science of life and healing system, a culture based health system of Nepal. This system was evolved primarily in the Himalaya through the deep meditation of ancient seekers and sheers. We can find the knowledge and health systems is being practiced in every households in Nepal . People around the world like to explore and experience the healing herbs, healing mountains and the healers. Ayurveda focuses on every dimension of life like promoting the health, harmonizing the body, senses,
    mind-emotions, and soul and also healing or curing of diseases.

    \n\nSo, walking through the different terrace and foothills and getting deeply touched by Ayurveda values is an excellent opportunity for tourists who like to visit Nepal. So, Ayurveda can provide many different modalities of therapies like whole body massages (different types), tranquilizing mind with Shirodhara and Cakra Basti and detoxifying internal organs. Stress has been epidemic throughout the world and managing with ancient wisdom and lifestyle management is the wonderful remedy. Here you find the high altitude medicinal plants which are encapsulating wonderful healing strength. So, you can enjoy Ayurveda healing touch along with other natural trekking or adventures in Pokhara.
</string>
    <string name="accomod">
        \n\nPokhara offers a wide variety of accommodation suited to almost all types of travelers varying from cheap backpacker’s guest houses to luxury 5 star and boutique hotels. The majority of hotels are around the Lakeside area, but for those looking for solitude; a number of more secluded options are available in the surrounding hills and towns. There are at least 500 tourist-standard hotels.
    </string>
    <string name="shop">
        \n\nPokhara has a variety of stores selling everything from traditional Nepali Pashminas and paper products to the latest trekking and mountaineering gear. Along the Lakeside, the streets are full of shops catering to the tourists. A selection of souvenirs, clothing and jewellery is also available. In addition, there are plenty of bookstores and DVD shops including a number of mini-markets which stock all the essential supplies needed by a traveler, including confectionary, toiletries, alcoholic drinks, and snacks.

\n\nIf you need something more, you can always find local shopping centers and supermarkets in the heart of the city where you can find traditional Nepali clothes, electronics, and other goods. Lakeside also offers a variety of other services, whether it is a relaxing massage after an arduous trekking adventure, a tattoo to remember your time in Nepal, or a yoga session to heal your mind and body.

\n\nIf you need to plan your next adventure, you can avail the services of a trekking or travel agency. While choosing an agency, make sure that it is a member of Trekking Agencies Association of Nepal (TAAN) or Nepal Association of Tour and Travel Agents (NATTA).
    </string>
    <string name="laundry">
        \n\nMost of the hotels in Lakeside offer in-house laundry services. Reliable laundry services are also available throughout Lakeside. The charges depend on the quantity of clothes and the timing. The services are reliable and well organized.
    </string>
    <string name="drink">
        \n\nBottled and mineral water is available in and around Pokhara. Many shops, offices and cafes have safe drinking water refill stations; they are the cheapest way to get drinking water in Pokhara. The water is from the same source as bottled water. We recommend you to use this facility and help reduce plastic waste.
    </string>
    <string name="food">
        \n\nPokhara is renowned for its cuisines, which includes western, continental, and local food. Numerous restaurants, cafeés, and bars are scattered around the main tourist area in Lakeside and in the main city of Pokhara. The restaurants and cafeés have a wide variety of styles and budgets, so you can find something that suits your inclination. In addition to cuisine, Lakeside has an exciting night life with many bars and pubs remaining open till late night. Many of these places offer a view of Phewa Lake and you can enjoy your drink with live music and cultural shows.

        \n\nPokhara is also famous for its Nepali or Thakali cuisine, especially Dal Bhat (rice and lintel). You will also have curried vegetables and meat, pickles, chutneys, papadam, green salad and curd. The most distinctive feature of Nepali cuisine is the use of spices and chilly. Chilies are an essential part of nearly every dish and are considered so important that most Nepali 
    </string>
    <string name="abc">
        \n\nAnnapurna Base Camp Trek traverses a variety of terrain from lowland villages, rice fields to glaciers. It provides an opportunity to surround yourself with great Himalaya peak in western region of Nepal. You will get a chance to get pampered yourself in a short period without having an altitude and flight problem. There is a 360 degrees mountain view while you are in the base camp.

\n\nDuration: 7 to 11 days
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate
\n\nMax. Elevation: 4130 m.
\n\nStart: Nayapul / Phedi / / Kande
\n\nAttractions:……..
    </string>
    <string name="ac">
        \n\nThe Annapurna circuit is considered by many to be the best trek in Nepal with a wonderful mixture of incredible mountain scenery of stunning views of Annapurna range and the culture. This trek passes through diverse Nepali villages and crosses the Thorung-La pass which touches the border of the Tibetan plateau. This trek can also combine together with the Tilicho lake (4919 m.) one of the highest lakes in the world, with extra trekking days.

\n\nDuration: 17 to 21 days
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate to Hard
\n\nMax. Elevation: 5416 m.
\n\nStart: Besisahar
    </string>
    <string name="kafuche">
        \n\nKafuche is the new Icelake of Nepal and becoming bigger every year because of global warming. The lake is situated 51 km north east from Pokhara and only in 8 hour walking distance from the famous village – Sillis.Trek to this lake is an amazing experience with lots of beautiful sceneries.

\n\nDuration: 5 to 7 days
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate
\n\nMax.elevation: 2437m
\n\nStart: Kahunkhola/ Bhurjungkhola
    </string>
    <string name="jomsom">
        \n\nThis trek is also known as pilgrims trek because of famous Muktinath temple and the holy place Kagbeni. This trek offers opportunity to explore old monasteries, ancient caves and scenic beauties. The route is combined with an incredible altitude, climate and cultural contrasts. This mainly covers the deepest gorge in-between the Annapurna and Dhaulagiri mountains which leads the trekkers from the well vegetated and fertile southern slop of Himalaya to the barren zone.

\n\nDuration: 5 – 12 days
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate
\n\nMax. Elevation: 3,800 m.
\n\nStart: Nayapul/ Jomsom
    </string>
    <string name="pun">
        \n\nThe Pun Hill trek is the most popular trek for those wanting a short introduction to trekking. Passing through scenic Gurung village and large rhododendron forest this trek offers spectacular views of the Annapurna and Dhaulagiri ranges.

\n\nDuration: 4 to 7 days
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate
\n\nMax. Elevation: 3,190 m.
\n\nStart: Nayapul / Phedi / / Kande/ Beni
    </string>
    <string name="Mardi">
        \n\nAs a relatively new trek, the route to Mardi Himal Base Camp is not only quiet and empty of trekkers but also adventurous and close to nature as the small path winds through huge forests. Though there is tea house accommodation until high camp, camping trek is most preferable. The trek to Mardi Himal Base Camp is best done as a day trip starting early in the morning for a stunning sunrise.

\n\nDuration: 5 to 7 days
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate to hard
\n\nMax. Elevation: 4,500 m.
\n\nStart: Kande
    </string>
    <string name="mustang">
        \n\nMustang is the quite fascinating destination for all. It is surrounded by northern snowy mountains, dotted with ancient forts, walled medieval villages and monasteries rich in Buddhist art, offers a fascinating glimpse into this remote enclave of Tibetan Culture. A deliberate policy of cultural and environmental preservation has meant that Mustang remains one of the world’s most special trekking destinations. Entry is limited and special trekking permits are required. 12 to 15 days should be allowed for Upper Mustang and it may also be combined with the Jomsom trek. Best time to visit this place is late March to November. A reasonable fitness level is required.

\n\nAlthough it was open for the tourists in 1990, the tourist arrival started only in 1992. Speedily blowing gushy air, barren desert, mound, and settlement inside the rocky cave, celestial houses made of local design and Buddhist Stupas and houses fluttering with its religious standards are the special peculiarities of Mustang.

\n\nDuration: 12 to 15 days
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate
\n\nMax. Elevation: 3,800 m.
\n\nStart: Jomsom
    </string>
    
 <string name="Nar">
     \n\nNar Phu is a combination of two remote villages. This trek traverses narrow canyons, lovely forests, ridiculous rock formations, yaks, monasteries and unique Himalayan cultures. This region was first explored by Tillman in the 1950s and Closed to trekkers until late 2002. The remoteness of the Nar Phu valley and its proximity to Tibet made that the people and their culture have remained more akin to Tibet than Nepal. The snow leopards and blue sheep are often seen in the area. The Phu is the most beautiful medieval village where you can learn the real life styles of Bhote communities enjoying and having a joyous typical lifestyle in the valley.

\n\nDuration: 15 -21 days
\n\nDifficulty: challenging
\n\nMax. Elevation: …..
\n\nStart: Koto via Besishar
 </string>

    <string name="dhaulagiri">
        \n\nWhite Mountain, which is separated from the Annapurna region by Kali Gandaki gorge, the deepest gorge in the world, includes some fifteen peaks above 7000 m. This region is considered to be one of the most remote places in the trans-Himalayan region in Nepal. And it has abundance of Himalayan peaks, hidden valleys, high passes and beautiful vistas. The trans-Himalayan journey is quiet, peaceful and full of adventure, gorgeous and excitement. Trekking in this area is relatively strenuous but trekkers willing to spend their holidays amidst true nature and its surroundings with full of peace and tranquility on the trekking attempt.

\n\nDuration: 15 to 18 days
\n\nDifficulty: challenging
\n\nMax. Elevation: 5,200 m.
\n\nStart: Beni
    </string>
    <string name="mansalu">
        \n\nManaslu is the newly opened region since 1991 for the trekkers. So it has still its own natural extraordinary virginity of beauty that every trekker can have the maximum satisfaction of nature’s paradise here. Trekking around Manaslu rewards you an excellent opportunity to experience in the exceptionally unvisited region of Nepal. Manaslu has unique ambiences, which is dastardly rich in bio-diversity that has made this region one of the finest eco tourism destinations of Nepal. The majestic Himalayan ranges in this area belonging to cultural diversities and natural sceneries with high altitude’s attractive glacier lakes and fascinating flora and fauna are all the valuable natural assets of this region.

\n\nDuration: 17 -19 days
\n\nDifficulty: challenging
\n\nMax. Elevation: 5,213 m.
\n\nStart: Gorkha
    </string>
    <string name="dhorpatan">
        \n\nDhorpatan is a national park covering 1325 sq. km. which was managed for conservation and the hunting of blue sheep and other game by the royal family and paying foreign parties. Now, of course, with the king deposed, official hunting has ceased and blue sheep, along with the musk deer, wolf, red panda and leopard are strictly protected. The area is important for potato and apple growing, mule breeding and is a distribution centre for salt and other goods brought in from Dolpo and Tibet.

\n\nThe name comes from the flat meadows above the 4000 m. high tree-line, which are locally known as Patans, and the marshy flat open valley next to which the village called Door is located. This trek offers extremely friendly people, wide well-made trails, pristine forest and meadows, sparkling rivers, and experience of a kind of way-out-there remote feeling. The paths on this trek are good, and altitude sickness is less likely to be a problem (compared with Dhaulagiri) as there is no real need to camp at high altitude.

\n\nDuration: 9 – 11 days
\n\nMax. Elevation: 4,600 m.
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate to hard
\n\nStart: Beni
    </string>
    <string name="panchase">
        \n\nPanchase Hill is the highest mountain surrounding Pokhara valley. It offers an interesting variety of terrain from low land village to outstanding high mountain views. From the top, one can have the opportunity to view all the mountain peaks of Dhaulagiri and Annapurna ranges to the north and many cities to the south even to the Indian border. Panchase is also famous in religious point of view.

\n\nDuration: 3 days
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate
\n\nMax. Elevation: 2,509 m.
\n\nStart: Pame/Lakeside
    </string>
    <string name="machapuchre">
        \n\nThis new trekking route offers mesmerizing views of snowcapped mountains of Annapurna, Fishtail and Mardi Himal from the close proximity and one can closely observe the indigenous life style and culture of diverse ethnic people. Beside this, the region is rich with unlimited flora and fauna, alpine forest, different species of birds, wild flowers, wild animals, and natural hot spring.

\n\nDuration: 5 days
\n\nMax. Elevation: 2645 m.
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate
n\\nStart: Milanchowk
    </string>
<string name="royal">
    \n\nThe Royal Trek is one of the famous and easiest treks in Annapurna region. The trek has got its name after Prince Charles and his 90 person entourage had explored this route in the early eighties. The trek passes through the ridges with magnificent views of snow capped mountains, villages and sub tropical forest. The trek is also reach in different cultures, landscapes, and vegetations and especially suitable for the beginners and elderly people or those who have very limited time but are looking for an opportunity to squeeze in a trekking holiday in the Himalayas.

\n\nDuration: 3-5 days
\n\nMax. Elevation: 1730 m.
\n\nTrekking type: Tea house, camping, home stay
\n\nDifficulty: Easy
</string>
    <string name="millenum">
        \n\nThe Millennium Trek, which is also known as Mid-hill Ridgeline Trek, lies on the South East of Pokhara and North East of Waling Bazaar. The starting altitude of the trek is 420 m. from sea level and the highest point is 1709 m. And it covers more than 30 colorful villages of Tanahun and Syangja district.

\n\nMillennium Trek in central Nepal offers diversity in landscapes with beautiful mountain views of Himalayan ranges from Kanjiroba to Ganesh Himal, mesmerizing sunset and sunrise view, cultural aspects of major ethnic groups of Nepal such as Gurung and Magar, the wave of underground water feature of Dhorbarahi temple, Millennium cave – an absolute natural cave with unique underground waterfalls, ancient temples, monasteries and historical forts. Most importantly this trekking route is not as tough as the other major trekking trails of Nepal. This trekking route also offers exotic sites for flora, fauna and wildlife. However, the route is untouched and still unknown to the foreigners and even to the domestic visitors.

\n\nDuration: 3 – 6 days
\n\nDifficulty: Moderate
\n\nMax. Elevation: 1,709m
\n\nStart: Gachhepani, Tanahu
    </string>
    <string name="gorkha">
        \n\nGorkha, an ancient capital of Prithivi Narayan Shah, Gorkha is Located 104 km. east from Pokhara and connected historically with the creation of the modern Nepal and the name of the legendary Gurkha soldiers. Four major rivers run within and along it, they are Chepe, Daraudi, Marsyangdi and Budhi Gandaki. It is a beautiful place with good view of Himalayan Mountains. Gorkha Palace, Gorakhkali temple, and Newari town are the special attractions. It is also the location of the Manakamana Temple which is accessible by cable car, only of its kind in Nepal.
    </string>
    <string name="bandipur">
        \n\nBandipur is located at an elevation of 1030 m. on a mountain saddle approximately 700 m. above the Marsyangdi River Valley. The mountain saddle, just 200 m. long, is barely wide enough to accommodate, the main street is lined by 2–3 storey buildings on either side.

\n\nIt is a charming hill town situated 8 km south of Dumre, on the way to Kathmandu and 68 Km east from Pokhara. This is a tranquil place and offers magnificent natural view and unique cultural experiences. Two major cultures of Magars and Newars can be seen surviving in harmony.
    </string>
    <string name="tansen">
        \n\nTansen is the administrative center of Palpa district in the hilly region of western Nepal. It is located on the highway, 122 km. south of Pokhara at an elevation of 1350 m. on the summit of the Mahabharat range. It is a typical Nepali town with numerous fairs, festivals, religious and cultural events. Non-polluted Tansen is one of the beautiful hill stations of Nepal.

\n\nNearby Srinagar Danda ‘hilltop’ (1525 m.) offers a panoramic view of the high Himalaya. From west to east, the Kanjiroba, Dhaulagiri, Annapurna, Mansiri, Ganesh and Langtang groups are in sight. Other nearby attractions includes Ranighat and Ridi Bazaar with holy river Ridi.
    </string>
    <string name="Chitwan">
        \n\nIt is the first national park of Nepal located 160 km. south from Pokhara. It has a rich flora and fauna and support species diversity much higher than any other on the Indian subcontinent. Rare species include Bengal tiger, ghariyal, rhino, leopard, mugger crocodile, Indian rock python and several species of deer.

\n\nThere are several hotels around the park and in Sauraha, provide food, accommodation and other services as per the client’s need including the wild life activities.

    </string>
    <string name="lumbini">
        \n\nIt is the birthplace of Gautama Buddha, the founder of Buddhism situated in 198 km. south-west from Pokhara and 22 km. from Bhairahawa. The site is a large garden with a grove of Pipal trees. The area around Lumbini is entirely Hindu, but many Buddhist temples and shrines from various nations are scattered around the holy site itself.

\n\nThe most important temple at Lumbini is the Maya Devi temple, which enshrines the traditional site of the Buddha’s birth. The current temple stands on the site of earlier temples and stupas, including the stupa built by Ashoka.

\n\nThe Maya Devi temple is surrounded by the brick foundations of ancient temples and monasteries. The other main sight of interest at Lumbini is Ashoka’s Pillar, near the temple. It is protected by a small fence, which is decorated with prayer flags and banners from the faithful.
    </string>
    <string name="dolpa">
        \n\nDolpa is the largest district of Nepal covering 5.36% of the total landmass of the country and the central concern of this area is Shey Phoksundo National Park. The park protects endangered animals like the snow leopard, musk deer and the Tibetan wolf. Shey Phoksundo is the largest and the only trans-Himalayan National Park in Nepal.

\n\nTrekking to Dolpa offers you the remarkable and breathtaking experience of a lifetime. The notable features seen here are snowy peaks, ancient and remote villages, rich wildlife, lovely Buddhist monasteries and wonderful lakes. The people of this area are simple and warm-hearted with an enthralling culture and traditions. The cultural traditions of this area are basically linked with the Tibetan culture.

\n\nTrekking into Dolpa presents an exposure to the high and remote Himalayan valleys, resembling the Tibetan highlands. The main highlight of Dolpa trekking includes Shey Phoksundo National Park, Shey Phoksundo Lake and the Shey Gompa. The lake is totally free of aquatic life, which the crystal waters clearly demonstrate. Surrounded by rocks, forests, and snow-capped peaks, the area has been described as one of the world’s “Natural Hidden Wonders”.

\n\nThis district, despite being the largest in area in the nation, has only one vehicle and no road links to other districts. So there is the only option either to trek all the way from Beni or Marpha or fly from Nepalgunj to Juphal.
    </string>
    <string name="get">
        \n\nTo/From Kathmandu
\n\nTourist bus: There are many tourist buses (AC and Non-AC) that depart every morning at 7 am from Kantipath near Thamel. The drive takes 7–8 hours depending upon the traffic and the road conditions and includes two stops for breakfast and lunch at roadside restaurants. The tourist bus station in Pokhara is located at the south of Lakeside, just one and half km. away from the center.

\n\nBy Air: There are several flights operated daily by domestic airlines between Kathmandu and Pokhara from 8 am to 3:30 pm. The flight can be arranged by local tour operators in Lakeside. The early morning flights can give you a spectacular view of the Himalayas. The flight duration is only 25 minutes and the Pokhara airport is just 2 km. away from Lakeside.

\n\nBy Car and Public Bus: There are many local/micro buses run daily from Kathmandu to Pokhara, and Pokhara to Kathmandu from early in the morning at 5 am to till late afternoon. These buses stop at Prithivi Chowk in Pokhara. You can also hire a car or Jeep from Kathmandu to Pokhara or vice versa. If you are in a small group like 3 to 7 people, it is best to drive by car or Jeep depending upon the group size, at least one way to experience the beauty of driving in Nepal with its natural beauties.

\n\nTo/From Indian Border
\n\nThe closest border to India is Sunauli (Belhiya) 184 km. to the south from Pokhara. There is no tourist bus service in between two cities: Pokhara and Sunauli. But there are daily buses leaving from Pokhara Tourist Bus Park to Bhairawa near Sunauli border at 6-7 am directly via Tansen and Butwal along the dramatic and beautiful Siddhartha Highway.
    </string>
    <string name="bird">
        \n\nBirds-In and Around
\n\nBegnas Lake, Rupa Lake, Khaste Lake, Neureni Lake, Dipang Lake, Maidi Lake, Gunde Lake, Kannani Danda, Bijayapur Khola Valley, Aarba-Bijaya, Kamal Pokhari, Kanhu Dada, Bhalam, Lamachaur, Seti Khola Valley, Astam, Dhampus, Thulakharka, Pitam Deurali, Kande, Bhadaure, Panchase, Fewa Watershed, Pumdibhumdi, Sarangkot, Fewa Lake, Phusre Khola, Bharat Pokhari, Nirmal Pokhari.



\n\nS.No.	English Name	Scientific Name	Local Name
\n\n1.	Hill Partridge	Arborophila torqueola	पिउरा
\n\n2.	Rufous-throated Partridge	Arborophila rufogularis	लालकण्ठे पिउरा
\n\n3.	Black Francolin	Francolinus francolinus	कालो तित्रा
\n\n4.	Common Quail	Coturnix coturnix	बट्टाई
\n\n5.	Kalij Pheasant	Lophura leucomelanos	कालिज
\n\n6.	Red Junglefoul	Gallus gallus	लुइ“चे
\n\n7.	Greylag Goose	Anser anser	कलहा“स
\n\n8.	Bar-headed Goose	Anser indicus	खोयाहा“स
\n\n9.	Lesser Whistling Duck	Dendrocygna javanica	सिलसिले
\n\n10.	Ruddy Shelduck	Tadorna ferruginea	चखेवाचखेवी
\n\n11.	Gadwall	Anas strepera	खडखडे हा“स
\n\n12.	Eurasian Wigeon	Anas penelope	सिन्द¬रे हा“स
\n\n13.	Mallard	Anas platyrhynchos	हरियोटाउके
\n\n14.	Indian Spot-billed Duck	Anas poecilorhyncha	नाद¬न हा“स
\n\n15.	Cotton Pygmy-goose	Nettapus coromandelianus	हरिहा“स
\n\n16.	Common Teal	Anas crecca	विज¬लागैरी
\n\n17.	Northern Pintail	Anas acuta	स¬ईरोप¬च्छ«े
\n\n18.	Northern Shoveler	Anas clypeata	बेल्चाठÒ“डे हा“स
\n\n19.	Red-crested Pochard	Rhodonessa rufina	स¬नज¬रे हा“स
\n\n20.	Common Pochard	Aythya ferina	कैलोटाउके हा“स
\n\n21.	Ferruginous Pochard	Aythya nyroca	मालक हा“स
\n\n22.	Tufted Duck	Aythya fuligula	कालीज¬रे हा“स
\n\n23.	Common Goldeneye	Bucephala clangula	स्वर्णनयन हा“स
\n\n24.	Goosander	Mergus merganser	मणित¬ण्डक
\n\n25.	Falcated Duck	Anas falcata	फुर्के हा“स
\n\n26.	Garganey	Anas querquedula	श्वेता“खीभौ
\n\n27.	Smew	Mergellus albellus	देवदुत मणितुण्डक
\n\n28.	Greater Scaup	Aythya marila	कालोटाउके हा“स
\n\n29.	Eurasian Wryneck	Jynx torquilla	खरलाहा“चे
\n\n30.	Yellow-rumped Honeyguide	Indicator xanthonotus	चाकासÒचक
\n\n31.	Darjeeling Woodpecker	Dendrocopos darjellensis	दार्जीलि∙ काष्टकÒट
\n\n32.	Speckled Piculet	Picumnus innominatus	थोप्ले ससिया
\n\n33.	Fulvous-breasted Woodpecker	Dendrocopos macei	काष्ठकÒट
\n\n34.	Bay Woodpecker	Blythipicus pyrrhotis	तामे लाहा“चे
\n\n35.	Lesser Yellownape	Picus chlorolophus	स¬नज¬रे काठफोर
\n\n36.	Greater Yellownape	Picus flavinucha	ठÒलो स¬नज¬रे काठफोर
\n\n37.	Grey-headed Woodpecker	Picus canus	कालोगर्दने काठफोर
\n\n38.	Scaly-bellied Woodpecker	Picus squamatus	ठूलोकत्ले काठफोर
\n\n39.	Greater Flameback	Chrysocolaptes lucidus	गर्दनगथोप्ले लाहा“चे
\n\n40.	Great Barbet	Megalaima virens	न्याउली
\n\n41.	Coppersmith Barbet	Megalaima haemacephala	मिलचरा
\n\n42.	Blue-throated Barbet	Megalaima asiatica	क¬थ¬र्के
\n\n43.	Golden-throated Barbet	Megalaima franklinii	क¬क्ल¬∙
\n\n44.	Common Hoopoe	Upupa epops	फाप्रे चरा
\n\n45.	Red-headed Trogon	Harpactes erythrocephalus	रक्तशिर
\n\n46.	Indian Roller	Coracias benghalensis	ठेउवा
\n\n47.	Chestnut-headed Bee-eater	Merops leschenaulti	कट¬सटाउके म¬रलीचरा
\n\n48.	Blue-bearded Bee-eater	Nyctyornis athertoni	मध¬मक्षी भक्षका
\n\n49.	Green Bee-eater	Merops orientalis	मुरलीचरा
\n\n50.	White-throated Kingfisher	Halcyon pileata	सेतोकण्ठे माटीकोरे
\n\n51.	Common Kingfisher	Alcedo atthis	सानो माटीकोरे
\n\n52.	Crested Kingfisher	Megaceryle lugubris	ठÒलो छिरबिरे माटीकोरे
\n\n53.	Pied Kingfisher	Ceryle rudis	छिरबिरे माटीकोरे
\n\n54.	Stork-billed Kingfisher	Halcyon capensis	ठूलो माटीकोरे
\n\n55.	Chestnut-winged Cuckoo	Clamator coromandus	ठÒलो ज¬रे कोइली
\n\n56.	Large Hawk Cuckoo	Hierococcyx sparverioides	पहाडी बीउ क¬हियो
\n\n57.	Common Hawk Cuckoo	Hierococcyx varius	बीउ क¬हियो
\n\n58.	Pied Cuckoo	Clamator jacobinus	जुरे कोइली
\n\n59.	Indian Cuckoo	Cuculus micropterus	काफल पाक्यो
\n\n60.	Eurasian Cuckoo	Cuculus canorus	क¬क्क¬ कोइली
\n\n61.	Oriental Cuckoo	Cuculus saturatus	पÒर्वीय कोइली
\n\n62.	Lesser Cuckoo	Cuculus poliocephalus	सानो कोइली
\n\n63.	Grey-bellied Cuckoo	Cacomantis passerinus	फ¬स्रे सानो कोइली
\n\n64.	Asian Koel	Eudynamys scolopacea	कोइली
\n\n65.	Green-billed Malkoha	Phaenicophaeus tristis	हरित मालकौवा
\n\n66.	Greater Coucal	Centropus sinensis	ढोडे गोक¬ल
\n\n67.	Sirkeer Malkoha	Phaenicophaeus tristis	न्याउरी मालकौवा
\n\n68.	Rose-ringed Parakeet	Psittacula krameri	कण्ठे स¬गा
\n\n69.	Alexandrine Parakeet	Psittacula eupatria	कर्रा स¬गा
\n\n70.	Slaty-headed Parakeet	Psittacula himalayana	मदना स¬गा
\n\n71.	Plum-headed Parakeet	Psittacula cyanocephala	टुइ“सी सुगा
\n\n72.	Red-breasted Parakeet	Psittacula alexandri	कागभेला सुगा
\n\n73.	Himalayan Swiftlet	Collocalia brevirostris	चींचिका गौंथली
\n\n74.	House Swift	Apus affinis	फिरफिरे घरगौंथली
\n\n75.	Alpine Swift	Tachymarptis melba	बतासी गौंथली
\n\n76.	Fork-tailed Swift	Apus pacificus	पुच्छरकापे गौथली
\n\n77.	White-throated Needletail	Hirundapus caudacutus	सेतोकण्ठे गौथली
\n\n78.	Barn Owl	Tyto alba	गोठे लाटोकोसेरो
\n\n79.	Mountain Scops Owl	Otus spilocephalus	लेकाली उलÒक
\n\n80.	Collared Scops Owl	Otus bakkamoena	चित्री उल¬क
\n\n81.	Asian Barred Owlet	Glaucidium cuculoides	ठÒलो डन्ड¬ल
\n\n82.	Jungle Owlet	Glaucidium radiatum	ड¬न्ड¬ल
\n\n83.	Spotted Owlet	Athene brama	कोचलगा“डे लाटोकोसेरो
\n\n84.	Eurasian Eagle Owl	Bubo bubo	हप्सिलो
\n\n85.	Spot-bellied Eagle Owl	Bubo nipalensis	महाकौशिक
\n\n86.	Brown Fish Owl	Ketupa zeylonensis	मलाहा ह¬चिल
\n\n87.	Brown Wood Owl	Strix leptogrammica	चश्मे उलÒक
\n\n88.	Grey Nightjar	Caprimulgus indicus	फ¬स्रो चैतेचरा
\n\n89.	Savana Nightjar	Caprimulgus affinis	चुइया“ चैतेचरा
\n\n90.	Brown Hawk Owl	Ninox scutulata	कालपेचक
\n\n91.	Short-eared Owl	Asio flammeus	लघूकर्ण
\n\n92.	Large-tailed Nightjar	Caprimulgus macrurus	लामपुच्छ«े चैतेचरा
\n\n93.	Rock Pigeon	Columba livia	मलेवा
\n\n94.	Speckleted Wood Pigeon	Columba hodgsonii	छिरबिरे वनपरेवा
\n\n95.	Oriental Turtle Dove	Streptopelia orientalis	तामे ढ¬क¬र
\n\n96.	Spotted Dove	Streptopelia chinensis	क¬र्ले ढ¬क¬र
\n\n97.	Red-collared Dove	Streptopelia tranquebarica	सानोतामे ढ¬क¬र
\n\n98.	Eurasian Collared Dove	Streptopelia decaocto	कण्ठे ढ¬क¬र
\n\n99.	Emerald Dove	Chalcophaps indica	हारल ढुकुर
\n\n100.	Barred Cuckoo Dove	Macropygia unchall	धर्के ढ¬क¬र
\n\n101.	Common Wood Pigeon	Columba palumbus	ठूलो बनपरेबा
\n\n102.	Orange-breasted Green Pigeon	Treron bicineta	सुन्तलेछाती हलेसो
\n\n103.	Wedge-tailed Green Pigeon	Treron sphenura	पहाडी हलेसो
\n\n104.	Yellow-footed Green Pigeon	Treron phoenicoptera	हलेसो
\n\n105.	Common Crane	Grus grus	लक्ष्मण सारस
\n\n106.	Black-necked Crane	Grus nigricollis	कालीकण्ठे सारस
\n\n107.	Demoiselle Crane	Grus virgo	क¥याङ—कुरुङ सारस
\n\n108.	White-breasted Waterhen	Amaurornis phoenicurus	सिमक¬ख¬रा
\n\n109.	Ruddy-breasted Crake	Porzana fusca	घोल कस्दरी
\n\n110.	Watercock	Gallicrex cinerea	जलक¬ख¬रा
\n\n111.	Purple Swamphen	Porphyrio porphyrio	क¬र्मा
\n\n112.	Common Moorhen	Gallinula chloropus	बगाले सिमक¬ख¬रा
\n\n113.	Eurasian Coot	Fulica atra	मरुल
\n\n114.	Solitary Snipe	Gallinago solitaria	भार्का चाहा
\n\n115.	Eurasian Woodcock	Scolopax rusticola	ठूलो चाहा
\n\n116.	Pintail Snipe	Gallinago stenura	भारक चाहा
\n\n117.	Common Snipe	Gallinago gallinago	पानी चाहा
\n\n118.	Jack Snipe	Lymnocryptes minimus	गोभण्डीर चाहा
\n\n119.	Greater Painted -snipe	Rostratula benghalensis	चित्रा∙द
\n\n119.	Wood Snipe	Gallinago nemoricola	वन चाहा
\n\n120.	Common Redshank	Tringa totanus	लालख¬ट्टे टिमटिमा
\n\n121.	Common Greenshank	Tringa nebularia	टिमटिमा
\n\n122.	Spotted Redshank	Tringa erythropus	थोप्ले टिमटिमा
\n\n123.	Green Sandpiper	Tringa ochropus	रुख स¬ड्स¬डिया
\n\n124.	Wood Sandpiper	Tringa glareola	वन स¬ड्स¬डिया
\n\n125.	Common Sandpiper	Actitis hypoleucos	चञ्चले स¬ड्स¬डिया
\n\n126.	Temminck’s Stint	Calidris temminckii	जलरड्ढ
\n\n127.	Black-winged Stilt	Himantopus himantopus	प्रवालपाद
\n\n128.	Pheasant-tailed Jacana	Hydrophasianus chirurgus	जलअप्सरा
\n\n129.	Bronze-winged Jacana	Metopidius indicus	लामाऔंले
\n\n130.	Little Ringed Plover	Charadrius dubius	लघ¬ राजप¬त्रिका
\n\n131.	Long-billed Plover	Charadrius placidus	लामठू“डे राजपुत्रिका
\n\n132.	Kentish Plover	Charadrius alexandrinus	अलकचन्द्र राजप¬त्रिका
\n\n133.	Dunlin	Calidris alpina	ठूलो जलरड्ढ
\n\n134.	Northern Lapwing	Vanellus vanellus	ज¬रे ह¬टिट्याउ“
\n\n135.	River Lapwing	Vanellus duvaucelii	खोले ह¬टिट्याउ“
\n\n136.	Grey-headed Lapwing	Vanellus cinereus	राजह¬टिट्याउ“
\n\n137.	Red-wattled Lapwing	Vanellus indicus	ह¬टिट्याउ“
\n\n138.	Pallas’s Gull	Larus ichthyaetus	राजा गंगाचिल
\n\n139.	Brown-headed Gull	Larus brunnicephalus	खैरोटाउके गंगाचिल
\n\n140.	Black-headed Gull	Larus ridibundus	कालोटाउके गंगाचिल
\n\n141.	Common Tern	Sterna hirundo	वाय¬ फ्याल्फ्याले
\n\n142.	Osprey	Pandion haliaetus	मलाहा चील
\n\n143.	Black Kite	Milvus migrans	कालो चील
\n\n144.	White-tailed Eagle	Haliaeetus albicilla	कड्ढक चील
\n\n145.	Brahminy Kite	Haliastur indus	सेतोटाउके चील
\n\n146.	White-rumped Vulture	Gyps bengalensis	डंगर गिद्घ
\n\n147.	Slender-billed Vulture	Gyps tenuirostris	सानो खैरो गिद्ध
\n\n148.	Egyptian Vulture	Neophron percnopterus	सेतो गिद्ध
\n\n149.	Himalayan Vulture	Gyps himalayensis	हिमाली गिद्ध
\n\n150.	Griffon Vulture	Gyps fulvus	खैरो गिद्ध
\n\n151.	Cinereous Vulture	Aegypius monachus	राजगिद्ध
\n\n152.	Red-headed Vulture	Sarcogyps calvus	स¬न गिद्ध
\n\n153.	Indian Vulture	Gyps indicus
\n\n154.	Crested Serpent Eagle	Spilornis cheela	काकाक¬ल
\n\n155.	Bearded Vulture	Gypaetus barbatus	हाडफोर
\n\n156.	Black Eagle	Ictinaetus malayensis	द्रोणक चील
\n\n157.	Hen Harrier	Circus cyaneus	चल्लाचोर भ¬इ“चील
\n\n158.	Eurasian Marsh Harrier	Circus aeruginosus	सिम भ¬इ“चील
\n\n159.	Pallid Harrier	Circus macrourus	श्वेत भ¬इ“चील
\n\n160.	Crested Goshawk	Accipiter trivirgatus	कल्की बेसरा
\n\n161.	Shikra	Accipiter badius	शिक्रा
\n\n162.	Besra	Accipiter virgatus	बेसरा
\n\n163.	Short-toed Snake Eagle	Circaetus gallicus	सर्पहारी चील
\n\n164.	Northern Goshawk	Accipiter gentilis	बलाकांक्ष वनवाज
\n\n165.	Long-legged Buzzard	Butro rufinus	लामख¬ट्टृ श्येनवाज
\n\n166.	Eurasian Sparrowhawk	Accipiter nisus	व्नबाज
\n\n167.	Oriental Honey-buzzard	Pernis ptilorhyncus	मध¬हा
\n\n168.	Common Buzzard	Buteo buteo	श्येनबाज
\n\n169.	Upland Buzzard	Buteo hemilasius	पहाडी श्येनबाज
\n\n170.	Golden Eagle	Aquila chrysatetos	स¬पर्ण महाचील
\n\n171.	Tawny Eagle	Aquila rapax	राग महाचील
\n\n172.	Eastern Imperial Eagle	Aquila heliaca	रणमत्त महाचील
\n\n173.	Steppe Eagle	Aquila nipalensis	गोमाय¬ महाचील
\n\n174.	Bonelli’s Eagle	Hieraaetus fasciatus	मोर∙ी चील
\n\n175.	Booted Eagle	Hieraaetus pennatus	का“धचन्द्र चील
\n\n176.	Mountain Hawk Eagle	Spizaetus nipalensis	पहाडी शदलचील
\n\n177.	Collared Falconet	Microhierax caerulescens	पौरी बाज
\n\n178.	Common Kestrel	Falco tinnunculus	बौडाइ
\n\n179.	Lesser Kestrel	Falco naumanni	सानो बौंडाइ
\n\n180.	Amur Falcon	Falco amurensis	अम¬र बाज
\n\n181.	Merlin	Falco columbarius	सानो बाज
\n\n182.	Peregrine Falcon	Falco peregrinus	शाही बाज
\n\n183.	Eurasian Hobby	Falco Subbuteo	जुंगे चिरान्तक बाज
\n\n184.	Little Grebe	Tachybaptus ruficollis	ड¬ब¬ल्कीचरा
\n\n185.	Great Crested Grebe	Podiceps cristatus	सिउरे ड¬ब¬ल्कीचरा
\n\n186.	Black-necked Grebe	Podiceps nigricollis	कालीकण्ठ ड¬ब¬ल्कीचरा
\n\n187.	Little Cormorant	Phalacrocorax niger	सानो जलेवा
\n\n188.	Great Cormorant	Phalacrocorax carbo	जलेवा
\n\n189.	Little Egret	Egretta garzetta	सानो सेतोबक¬ल्ला
\n\n190.	Cattle Egret	Bubulcus ibis	वस्त¬ बक¬ल्ला
\n\n191.	Great Egret	Casmerodius albus	ठÒलो सेतोबक¬ल्ला
\n\n192.	Intermediate Egret	Mesophoyx intermedia	मझौला सेतोबक¬ल्ला
\n\n193.	Grey Heron	Ardea cinerea	फ¬स्रो बक¬ल्ला
\n\n194.	Indian Pond Heron	Ardeola grayii	आसकोटे बक¬ल्ला
\n\n195.	Little Heron	Butorides striatus	छोटाख¬ट्टे बक¬ल्ला
\n\n196.	Black-crowned Night Heron	Nycticorax nycticorax	बा“के बक¬ल्ला
\n\n197.	Cinnamon Bittern	Ixobrychus cinnamomeus	रातो जÒनबक¬ल्ला
\n\n198.	Yellow Bittern	Ixobrychus sinensis	पहेलो जूनबकुल्ला
\n\n199.	Black Bittern	Dupetor flavicollis	कालो जूनबकुल्ला
\n\n200.	Woolly-necked Stork	Ciconia episcopus	लोभीपापी गरुड
\n\n201.	Black Stork	Ciconia nigra	कालो गरुड
\n\n202.	Long-tailed Broadbill	Psarisomus dalhousiae	चित्रकÒट
\n\n203.	Blue-naped Pitta	Pitta nipalensis	नेपाल पिट्टा
\n\n204.	Orange-bellied Leafbird	Chloropsis hardwickii	स्वर्णोदर हरितचरी
\n\n205.	Golden-fronted Leafbird	Chloropsis aurifrons	कृष्णकण्ठे हरितचरी
\n\n206.	Long-tailed Shrike	Lanius schach	भद्राई
\n\n207.	Grey-backed Shrike	Lanius tephronotus	हिमाली भद्राई
\n\n208.	Brown Shrike	Lanius cristatus	खैरो भद्राई
\n\n209.	Bay-backed Shrike	Lanius vittatus	चित्रक भद्राई
\n\n210.	Eurasian Jay	Garrulus glandarius	कैले बनकाग
\n\n211.	Black-headed Jay	Garrulus lanceolatus	कालोटाउके बनकाग
\n\n212.	Yellow-billed Blue Magpie	Urocissa flavirostris	स¬नठÒ“डे लामप¬च्छ«े
\n\n213.	Red-billed Blue Magpie	Urocissa erythorhyncha	स्यालपोथरी लामप¬च्छे«
\n\n214.	Grey Treepie	Dendrocitta formosae	पहाडी कोकले
\n\n215.	Rufous Treepie	Dendrocitta vagabunda	कोकले
\n\n216.	Common Green Magpie	Cissa chinensis	हरियो लामप¬च्छ«े
\n\n217.	Large-billed Crow	Corvus macrorhynchos	कालो काग
\n\n218.	House Crow	Corvus splendens	घर काग
\n\n219.	Ashy Woodswallow	Artamus fuscus	भिथुन
\n\n220.	Indian Golden Oriole	Oriolus oriolus	गाजले स¬नचरी
\n\n221.	Maroon Oriole	Oriolus traillii	घनरक्त स¬नचरी
\n\n222.	Slender-billed Oriole	Oriolus tenuirostris	तीखोठू“डे सुनचरी
\n\n223.	Large Cuckooshrike	Coracina macei	लट¬शक विरहीचरी
\n\n224.	Black-winged Cuckooshrike	Coracina melanoptera	कालो विरहीचरी
\n\n225.	Small Minivet	Pericrocotus cinnamomeus	सानो रानीचरी
\n\n226.	Grey-chinned Minivet	Pericrocotus solaris	नौनीकण्ठे रानीचरी
\n\n227.	Long-tailed Minivet	Pericrocotus ethologus	लामप¬च्छे« रानीचरी
\n\n228.	Scarlet Minivet	Pericrocotus flammeus	रानीचरी
\n\n229.	Yellow-bellied Fantail	Rhipidura hypoxantha	पहेंलो मारुनीचरी
\n\n230.	White-throated Fantail	Rhipidura albicollis	नक्कले मारुनीचरी
\n\n231.	Black Drongo	Dicrurus macrocercus	कालो चिबे
\n\n232.	Ashy Drongo	Dicrurus leucophaeus	ध्वा“से चिबे
\n\n233.	Spangled Drongo	Dicrurus hottentottus	केशराज चिबे
\n\n234.	Bronzed Drongo	Dicrurus aeneus	सानो चिबे
\n\n235.	Lesser Racket-tailed Drongo	Dicrurus remifer	भृ∙राज चिबे
\n\n236.	White-bellied Drongo	Dicrurus caerulescens	सेतोपेटे चिबे
\n\n237.	Common Iora	Aegithina tiphia	स¬सेलीचरा
\n\n238.	Large Woodshrike	Tephrodornis gularis	ठÒलो टेन्था
\n\n239.	Brown Dipper	Cinclus pallasii	खैरो वन्जÒल
\n\n240.	Blue-capped Rock Thrush	Monticola cinclorhynchus	सानो हजारा चा“चर
\n\n241.	Blue Rock Thrush	Monticola solitarius	उमा चा“चर
\n\n242.	Asian Paradise Flycatcher	Terpsiphone paradise	स्वर्गचरी
\n\n243.	Orange-headed Thrush	Zoothera citrina	स¬न्तले चा“चर
\n\n244.	Blue Whistling Thrush	Myophonus caeruleus	कल्चौंडे
\n\n245.	Chestnut-bellied Rock Thrush	Monticola rufiventris	हजारा चा“चर
\n\n246.	Scaly Thrush	Zoothera dauma	गोबे्र चा“चर
\n\n247.	White-collared Blackbird	Turdus albocinctus	कण्ठे चा“चर
\n\n248.	Grey-winged Blackbird	Turdus boulboul	मदना चा“चर
\n\n249.	Dark-throated Thrush	Turdus ruficollis	कालीकण्ठे चा“चर
\n\n250.	Dark-sided Flycatcher	Muscicapa sibirica	ध्वा“से अजर्¬नक
\n\n251.	Rufous-gorgetted Flycatcher	Ficedula strophiata	सेतोटिके अजर्¬नक
\n\n252.	Taiga Flycatcher	Ficedula albiclla	लालकण्ठे अजर्¬नक
\n\n253.	Slaty-backed Flycatcher	Ficedula hodgsonii	नीलढाडे अर्जुनक
\n\n254.	Snowy-browed Flycatcher	Ficedula hyperythra	सेतोआ“खीभौ अर्जुनक
\n\n255.	Little Pied Flycatcher	Ficedula westermanni	श्यामश्वेत अजर्¬नक
\n\n256.	Ultramarine Flycatcher	Ficedula superviliaris	नीलश्वेत अजर्¬नक
\n\n257.	Slaty-blue Flycatcher	Ficedula tricolor	टिकटिके अर्जुनक
\n\n258.	Sapphire Flycatcher	Ficedula sapphire	नीलमणि अर्जुनक
\n\n259.	Grey-headed Canary Flycatcher	Culicicapa ceylonensis	चञ्चले अजर्¬नक
\n\n260.	Verditer Flycatcher	Eumyias thalassinus	नीलत¬थो अजर्¬नक
\n\n261.	Large Niltava	Niltava grandis	ठूलो नीलतभा
\n\n262.	Small Niltava	Niltava magrigoriae	सानो नीलतभा
\n\n263.	Rufous-bellied Niltava	Niltava sundara	स¬न्दर नीलतभा
\n\n264.	Bluethroat	Luscinia svecica	भुमिचर नीलकण्ठ
\n\n265.	Pale Blue Flycatcher	Cyornis unicolor	नौनीकण्ठे अजर्¬नक
\n\n266.	Siberian Rubythroat	Luscinia calliope	साइबेरियाली रातोकण्ठे
\n\n267.	White-tailed Rubythroat	Luscinia pectoralis	हिमाली रातोकण्ठे
\n\n268.	White-browed Shortwing	Brachypteryx montana	नीलो लघुपंख
\n\n269.	Indian Blue Robin	Luscinia brunnea	नीलो रबिन
\n\n270.	Oriental Magpie Robin	Copsychus saularis	धोबिनी चरी
\n\n271.	Himalayan Bluetail	Tarsiger cyanurus	स¬न्तलाकोखे रबिन
\n\n272.	Golden Bush Robin	Tarsiger chrysaeus	स¬नौलो रबिन
\n\n273.	Hodgson’s Redstart	Phoenicurus hodgsoni	तनकम्प खञ्जरी
\n\n274.	White-capped Redstart	Chaimarrornis leucocephalus	सेतोटाउके जलखञ्जरी
\n\n275.	Plumbeous Water Redstart	Rhyacornis fuliginosus	नीलाम्बर जलखञ्जरी
\n\n276.	Rufous-backed Redstart	Phoenicurus erythronota	कैलोढाडे खञ्जरी
\n\n277.	Black Redstart	Phoenicurus ochruros	ध्याप्ची खञ्जरी
\n\n278.	Little Forktail	Enicurus scouleri	गंगा खोलेधाबिनी
\n\n279.	Black-blacked Forktail	Enicurus immaculatus	कालोढाडे खोलेधोबिनी
\n\n280.	Slaty-backed Forktail	Enicurus schistaceus	फ¬स्रोढाडे खोलेधोबिनी
\n\n281.	Spotted Forktail	Enicurus maculatus	थोप्ले खोलेधोबिनी
\n\n282.	Grey Bushchat	Saxicola ferrea	हिमाली झ्याप्सी
\n\n283.	Common Stonechat	Saxicola torquata	झेकझेक झ्याप्सी
\n\n284.	Pied Bushchat	Saxicola caprata	काले झ्याप्सी
\n\n285.	Isabelline Wheatear	Oenanthe isabellina	फुस्रो भूइ“रबिन
\n\n286.	Spot-winged Starling	Saroglossa spiloptera	कटुसकण्ठे सारौं
\n\n287.	Common Myna	Acridotheres tristis	डाङग्रे रुपी
\n\n288.	Jungle Myna	Acridotheres fuscus	वन रुपी
\n\n289.	Chestnut-tailed Starling	Sturnus malabaricus	फ¬स्रोटाउके सारौं
\n\n290.	Brahminy Starling	Sturnus pagodarum	ज¬रे सारौं
\n\n291.	Velvet-fronted Nuthatch	Sitta frontalis	मखमली मट्टा
\n\n292.	Chestnut-bellied Nuthatch	Sitta castanea	कट¬से मट्टा
\n\n293.	White-tailed Nuthatch	Sitta himalayansis	पहाडी मट्टा
\n\n294.	Wallcreeper	Tichodroma muraria	म¬रारी प¬तलीचरा
\n\n295.	Brown-throated Treecreeper	Certhia discolor	खैरो छेपारेचरी
\n\n296.	Rufous-vented Tit	Parus rubidiventris	सेतोगर्दने चिचिल्कोटे
\n\n297.	Grey-crested Tit	Parus dichrous	फुस्रोजुरे चिचिल्कोटे
\n\n298.	Great Tit	Parus major	चिचिल्कोटे
\n\n299.	Green-backed Tit	Parus monticolus	हरियो चिचिल्कोटे
\n\n300.	Black-lored Tit	Parus xanthogenys	पाण्ड¬ चिचिल्कोटे
\n\n301.	Yellow-checket Tit	Parus spilonotus	पीतमुहार चिचिल्कोटे
\n\n302.	Black-throated Tit	Aegithalos concinnus	कालीकण्ठे चिचिल्कोटे
\n\n303.	Winter Wren	Troglodytes troglodytes	चित्री
\n\n304.	Plain Martin	Riparia paludicola	भित्तेगौंथली
\n\n305.	Eurasian Crag Martin	Hirundo rupestris	नहिकुटी गौंथली
\n\n306.	Asian House Martin	Delichon dasypus	एशियाली भीरगौंथली
\n\n307.	Barn Swallow	Hirundo rustica	घर गौंथली
\n\n308.	Red-rumped Swallow	Hirundo daurica	गेरुकटी गौंथली
\n\n309.	Red-vented Bulbul	Pycnonotus cafer	ज¬रेली
\n\n310.	Himalayan Bulbul	Pycnonotus leucogenys	ज¬ल्फे ज¬रेली
\n\n311.	Black Bulbul	Hypsipetes leucocephalus	बाख्रे ज¬रेली
\n\n312.	Ashy Bulbul	Hemixos flavala	फ¬स्रोपाटे ज¬रेली
\n\n313.	Mountain Bulbul	Hypsipetes mcclellandii	कैलोपेटे ज¬रेली
\n\n314.	Striated Bulbul	Pycnonotus striatus	धर्के जुरेली
\n\n315.	Black-crested Bulbul	Pycnonotus melanicterus	कालोकल्की पहेंलोजुरेली
\n\n316.	Striated Prinia	Prinia criniger	स¬या घा“सेफिस्टो
\n\n317.	Zitting Cisticola	Cisticola juncidis	फिर्फिरे
\n\n318.	Oriental White-eye	Zosterops palpebrosus	कांकीर
\n\n319.	Chestnut-headed Tesia	Tesia castaneocoronata	रातोटाउके टिसिया
\n\n320.	Grey-bellied Tesia	Tesia cyaniventer	फ¬स्रोपेटे टिसिया
\n\n321.	Common Tailorbird	Orthotomus sutorius	पातसिउने फिस्टो
\n\n322.	Grey-sided Bush Warbler	Cettia brunnifrons	रातोटाउके झाडिफिस्टो
\n\n323.	Common Chiffchaff	Phylloscopus collybita	चिप्चिपे फिस्टो
\n\n324.	Chestnut-crowned Bush Warbler	Cettia major	ठूलो रातोटाउके झाडिफिस्टो
\n\n325.	Aberrant Bush Warbler	Cettia flavolivacea	पीतोदर झाडिफिस्टो
\n\n326.	Smoky Warbler	Phylloscopus fulgiventer	ध्वा“से फिस्टो
\n\n327.	Western Crowned Warbler	Phylloscopus occipitalis	ठÒलो ताल¬धर्के फिस्टो
\n\n328.	Lemon-rumped Warbler	Phylloscopus chloronotus	पीतकटी फिस्टो
\n\n329.	Greenish Warbler	Phylloscopus trochiloides	जीवल फिस्टो
\n\n330.	Grey-hooded Warbler	Seicercus xanthoschistos	त¬म¬लकारी फिस्टो
\n\n331.	Ashy-throated Warbler	Phylloscopus maculipennis	फुस्रोकण्ठे फिस्टो
\n\n332.	Hume’s Warbler	Phylloscopus humei	चञ्चले फिस्टो
\n\n333.	Golden-spectacled Warbler	Seicercus burkii	स¬नचश्मे फिस्टो
\n\n334.	Whistler’s Warbler	Seicercus whistleri	सुसेली फिस्टो
\n\n335.	Black-faced Warbler	Abroscopus schisticeps	गाजले फिस्टो
\n\n336.	Blyth’s Leaf Warbler	Phylloscopus occipitalis	तालुधर्के फिस्टो
\n\n337.	White-throated Laughingthrush	Garrulax albogularis	सोइरने तोरीगा“डा
\n\n338.	White-crested Laughingthrush	Garrulax leucolophus	हिउ“ज¬रे तोरीगा“डा
\n\n339.	Lesser Necklaced Laughingthrush	Garrulax monileger	सानोकण्ठे तोरीगा“डा
\n\n340.	Striated Laughingthrush	Garrulax striatus	कल्की तोरीगा“डा
\n\n341.	Streaked Laughingthrush	Garrulax lineatus	छिर्के तोरीगा“डा
\n\n342.	Rufous-chined Laughingtrush	Garrulax rufogularis	कैलोकण्ठे तोरीगा“डा
\n\n343.	Chestnut-crowned Laughingthrush	Garrulax erythrocephalus	कटुसटाउके तोरीगा“डा
\n\n344.	Scaly Laughingthrush	Garrulax subunicolor	कत्ले तोरीगा“डा
\n\n345.	Puff-throated Babbler	Pellorneum ruficeps	थोप्ले भ्याक¬र
\n\n346.	Rusty-cheeked Scimitar Babbler	Pomatorhinus erythrogenys	पाल्कोटे
\n\n347.	White-browed Scimitar Babbler	Pomatorhinus schisticeps	फ¬स्रोटाउके पाल्कोटे
\n\n348.	Scaly-breasted Wren Babbler	Pnoepyga albiventer	कत्ले डिक¬रेभ्याक¬र
\n\n349.	Pygmy Wren Babbler	Pnoepyga pusilla	म¬सालि“डे डिक¬रेभ्याक¬र
\n\n350.	Nepal Wren Babbler	Pnoepyga immaculata	नेपाल डिक¬रेभ्याक¬र
\n\n351.	Black-chinned Babbler	Stachyris pyrrhops	कालोचिउ“डे वनभ्याक¬र
\n\n352.	Golden Babbler	Stachyris chrysaea	निगाले वनभ्याकुर
\n\n353.	Spiny Babbler	Turdoides nipalensis	का“डे भ्याक¬र
\n\n354.	Jungle Babbler	Turdoides striatus	बगाले भ्याकुर
\n\n355.	Red-billed Leiothrix	Leiothrix lutea	रोचिष्णु मिसिया
\n\n356.	Sliver-eared Mesia	Leiothrix argentauris	चा“दीकाने मिसिया
\n\n357.	Cutia	Cutia nipalensis	कुटिया
\n\n358.	White-browed Shrike Babbler	Pteruthius falviscapis	लालपंखे भद्राईभ्याकुर
\n\n359.	Black-eared Shrike Babbler	Pteruthius rufiventer	कालोटाउके भद्राईभ्याकुर
\n\n360.	Bar-throated Siva	Minla strigula	शिव मिन्ला
\n\n361.	Blue-winged Minla	Minla cyanouroptera	नीलपंख मिन्ला
\n\n362.	Hoary-throated Barwing	Actinodura nipalensis	वनचाहर
\n\n363.	Rufous-winged Fulvetta	Alcippe castaneceps	कट¬सटाउके फÒलब¬ट्टा
\n\n364.	White-browed Fulvetta	Alcippe vinipectus	पीतनयन फÒलब¬ट्टा
\n\n365.	Whiskered Yuhina	Yuhina flavicollis	ज¬ंगे ज¬रेचरा
\n\n366.	Stripe-throated Yuhina	Yuhina gularis	थ¬पलकल्की ज¬रेचरा
\n\n367.	Rufous-vented Yuhina	Yuhina occipitalis	खैरो ज¬रेचरा
\n\n368.	White-bellied Yuhina	Yuhina zantholeuca	सेतोपेटे ज¬रेचरा
\n\n369.	Nepal Fulvetta	Alcippe nipalensis	नेपाल फूलबुट्टा
\n\n370.	Rufous Sibia	Heterophasia capistrata	सियिबा
\n\n371.	Thick-billed Flowerpecker	Dicacum agile	मोटोठू“डे प¬ष्पकोकिल
\n\n372.	Pale-billed Flowerpecker	Dicacum erythrorynchos	रातोठू“डे प¬ष्पकोकिल
\n\n373.	Yellow-bellied Flowerpecker	Dicacum melanoxanthum	पीतोदर प¬ष्पकोकिल
\n\n374.	Fire-breasted Flowerpecker	Dicacum ignipectus	अग्निवक्ष प¬ष्पकोकिल
\n\n375.	Purple Sunbird	Nectarinia asiatica	कालो ब¬∙ेचरा
\n\n376.	Green-tailed Sunbird	Aethopyga nipalensis	नेपाल ब¬∙ेचरा
\n\n377.	Black-throated Subird	Aethopyga saturat	कालीकण्ठे ब¬∙ेचरा
\n\n378.	Crimson Sunbird	Aethopyga siparaja	सिपराजा ब¬∙ेचरा
\n\n379.	Fire-tailed Sunbird	Aethopyga ignicauda	लालप¬च्छ«े ब¬∙ेचरा
\n\n380.	House Sparrow	Passer domesticus	घर भ“गेरा
\n\n381.	Russet Sprrow	Passer rutilans	कैलो भ“गेरा
\n\n382.	Eurasian Tree Sparrow	Passer montanus	रुख भ“गेरा
\n\n383.	Grey Wagtail	Motacilla cinerea	फ¬स्रो टिकटिके
\n\n384.	White Wagtail	Motacilla alba	सेतो टिकटिके
\n\n385.	Yellow Wagtail	Motacilla flava	पहेंलो टिकटिके
\n\n386.	Citrine Wagtail	Motacilla citreola	बेसारे टिकटिके
\n\n387.	White-browed Wagtail	Motacilla maderaspatensis	खोले टिकटिके
\n\n388.	Richard’s Pipit	Anthus richardi	हिउ“दे च¬इया“
\n\n389.	Paddyfield Pipit	Anthus rufulus	आली च¬इया“
\n\n390.	Upland Pipit	Anthus syvanus	पहाडी च¬इया“
\n\n391.	Olive-backed Pipit	Anthus hodgsoni	रुख च¬ईया“
\n\n392.	Rosy Pipit	Anthus roseatus	ग¬लाफीकण्ठे च¬ईया“
\n\n393.	Red-throated Pipit	Anthus cervinus	लालकण्ठे च¬ईया“
\n\n394.	Water Pipit	Anthus spinoletta	जल च¬ईया“
\n\n395.	Rufous-breasted Accentor	Prunella strophiata	मुसे लेकचरी
\n\n396.	Baya Weaver	Ploceus philippinus	बया तोपचरा
\n\n397.	White-rumped Munia	Lonchura striata	सेतोढाडे म¬निया“
\n\n398.	Scaly-breasted Munia	Lonchura punctulata	कोटेरो म¬निया“
\n\n399.	Black-headed Munia	Lonchura malacca	कालोटाउके मुनिया“
\n\n400.	Dark-breasted Rosefinch	Carpodacus nipalensis	नेपाल तितु
\n\n401.	Common Rosefinch	Carpodacus erythrinus	अमोंगा तितु
\n\n402.	Beautiful Rosefinch	Carpodacus pulcherrimus	झिबी तितु
\n\n403.	Pink-browed Rosefinch	Carpodacus rodochrous	रातो झिबी तितु
\n\n404.	Scarlet Finch	Haematospiza sipahi	सिपाही तितु
\n\n405.	Brown Bullfinch	Pyrrhula nipalensis	खैरो टिउ“टिउ“
\n\n406.	Red-headed Bullfinch	Pyrrhula erythrocephala	रातोटाउके टिउ“टिउ“
\n\n407.	Golden-naped Finch	Pyrrhoplectes epauletta	सुन्तलेटाउके कालेतितु
\n\n408.	Spot-winged Grosbeak	Mycerobas melanozanthos	पंखथोप्ले महाठू“ड
\n\n409.	Crested Bunting	Melophus lathami	ज¬रे बगेडी
\n\n410.	Yellow-breasted Bunting	Emberiza aureola	बगाले बगेडी
\n\n411.	Black-faced Bunting	Emberiza spodocephala	कृष्णमुहार बगेडी
ीयअब िल्बmभ
    </string>
    <string name="weather">
        \n\nNepal climate varies according to its season. Autumn and spring are the two most favorable seasons for trekking in Nepal. Autumn starts from early September to early December and brings in clear weather with sunny days and warm nights. Whereas spring starts from the beginning of March to the end of May with occasional rain falls. From June to September, is the monsoon season. Trekking is generally difficult and uncomfortable as the climate of Nepal at this time of year brings about hot weather and rain falls almost every day. The trails become muddy and are often leech-infested. Moreover, the mountains are usually obscured by cloud. There are, however, possibilities for summer trekking in the trans-Himalayan regions of Mustang, Dolpo and Humla. These regions lie in a rain-shadow and therefore receive significantly less precipitation than the more southerly areas.

\n\nAutumn (September to November)
\nAutumn is an ideal time to visit Nepal. The countryside is green and lush and Nepal looks its most beautiful. The air is sparkling clean, affording near perfect Himalayan vistas. As the weather is neither too hot nor too cold, this is peak tourist season and it is also the main season for Nepalese festivals. However, in the higher altitude, the nights drop into freezing temperature. In this season, the mountains views are astonishingly clear.

\n\nWinter (December to February)
\nWinter can be a hauntingly beautiful time of the year to trek. The climate and visibility are still good, excellent clear views are common at high altitude but it can get very cold. You need to be prepared to encounter snow on the high altitudes and the higher passes may be closed.

\n\nSpring (March to May)
\nIn spring, the mornings are usually clear but afternoon cloud build-up brings occasional showers. The days are mix up with warm and rain, which displays wildflowers like rhododendrons. The whole country is lush and an abundant green at this season. This period instigate the second most popular and pleasant trekking season as this is rice-planting time. Late-march into April is especially beautiful. It is also a good time for climbing as the high passes are usually snow free and the mountain views are still clear in April. Up to May, the weather becomes hazy and disturbed with the clouds.

\n\nMonsoon (June to August)
\nJune to August is warm and wet but these months are blessed for the keen botanist as the higher valleys and meadows blossom with flowers and lush vegetation. Generally the morning is cloudy and the cloud wisps form on random ridges and peaks. Trekking at this time of year is generally uncomfortable as the weather is hot and the rains. There are, however, possibilities for trekking in the trans-Himalayan regions of mustang, Dolpo and Tibet. These regions lie in a rain-shadow and therefore receive significantly less precipitation than the more southerly areas.
    </string>
    <string name="pokhara">
        \n\nPresence of panoramic view of Western Himalayan ranges like Fishtail, Annapurna and Dhaulagiri etc. and surrounded by various vegetations of the mid hills and inhabitants of incredible cultural practices of multi-ethnic groups are the essence of this tiny town Pokhara in Nepal. This is also a place beautified with its natural gifts of lakes, flora and fauna, caves, gorges where pilgrims or worshipers have access to popular temples, mosques, churches and monasteries. Pokhara can be considered as an ideal and one of the most preferred destinations because of its unique combination of the characteristics of both nature and culture.
    </string>
    <string name="history">
        \n\nInitially, Pokhara was explored as a transit point for mountaineers around 1950 and 1960. It was explored by a few thousand tourists in 1962. The first historic ascend of Mt. Annapurna (8091 m.) on June 3, 1950 by a French national Maurice Herzog and a team of mountaineers was the historic pioneer step in exposing Pokhara as a mountainous tourist destination in the world. Dr. Tony Hagen, the Swiss Geographer visited Pokhara in 1950. British Colonel Jimmy Roberts in association with globally pioneer package tourism inventor, Thomas Cook (United Kingdom) in 1966 added another milestone for the exposition of Pokhara and its surrounding areas from the perspective of tourism. However, the literature shows that it was popular among the visitors even before the century as quoted in the travelogues published by E. Kawaguchi (1899). It is a fortune for all of us which also deserves our responsibility of saving and preserving this gift and make presentable for all. A sense of collective effort emerges not only for its preservation but also to expose such paradise on earth to the world’s people. Pokhara is the transit point for the tourists intending to go to Annapurna region. That is why tourists first arrive Pokhara and then proceed to Annapurna area. Those who have planned to visit Pokhara, are also found to be fascinated to visit Annapurna area too as they hear and see about it. So, the Annapurna region and Pokhara are interconnected and inseparable from tourism point of view.

\n\nHippies were also the first Westerners to reach Pokhara in Western region in the 1970s. From the time of the monk Ekai Kawaguchi who travelled Nepal and visited Pokhara in 1899 to Maurice Herzog’s climbing expedition in 1950 and Toni Hagen’s geographical researching tour in 1952, Pokhara was visited by fewer foreigners. However, it was the Hippie era which made not only Nepal but also Pokhara famous in European and American markets. The year 1970, when hippies started coming to Pokhara making significant change in tourism, can be considered the opening decade of modern tourism in Pokhara. They have enormous roles for exploring new mountainous tourist sites that contributed to the identification of new trekking routes and sites in Annapurna and other regions of Nepal.
    </string>
<string name="why">
   \n\n1. The Pokhara valley is full of lush vegetation, swift flowing rivers and dotted with clear, shimmering lakes.

    n\n 2.140 km. of panorama made up of towering Himalayan ranges seen from Pokhara close enough likely to be touched on a clear day.
\n\n 3.Pokhara is the only place in the world from where one can see the 3 high mountains above 8,000 m. – Annapurna, Dhaulagiri and Manaslu with their naked eye.
\n\n 4.It is a gateway to the world famous Annapurna circuit trekking trail.
\n\n 5.It is a prime destination for adventure sports like, paragliding, ultra-light flights, bungee jumps , zip line , rafting/kayaking, stand up paddling, boating, bird watching, trekking, rock climbing and mountain biking etc.
\n\n 6.The relaxed atmosphere on the shores of Phewa Lake gives a trekker a much needed respite from days of hiking up and down the hills and mountains.
\n\n 7.The enchanting Pokhara valley with the dominating presence of Mt. Machhapuchhare (Fishtail mountain) in the background is the gateway to the Annapurna region where many a trekker finds one’s Shangri-la.
\n\n 8.The crowded bars and restaurants are the places to seek companionship, where tall stories and real life experiences are shared with perfect strangers. The friendly Nepalese make a tourist feel at home to the point where many stay on for extended periods and come each year to seek those friends he’s made and find peace of mind.
\n\n 9.City of Lakes: Many freshwater lakes are located in the south and east of the Pokhara Valley. The Annapurna range on the North is only about 28 km. (linear distance) away from the Phewa Lake, and the lake is famous for the reflection of mount Machhapuchhre and other mountain peaks of the Annapurna and Dhaulagiri ranges on its surface.
</string>
    <string name="president">
        \n\nIt is our pleasure to come with the Pokhara Tourism Council official website. We are hopeful that it will support the promotion of tourism in the region and the country. Known as the land of paradise, Pokhara is really famous for its natural beauty, cultural varieties and for attractive events and activities .Previously the country passed through a turbulent situation disturbing almost all the nerves of our nation for some years. Before the time of recovery period, the country witnessed the problem of earth quake and now again with border blockade, which ultimately hampered all the economic activities including the tourism of Nepal. Despite these problems and turbulences, the country succeeded to achieve the new constitution from the constituent assembly. It will certainly help to create a peaceful socio situation and dynamism for the economic activity in the country and hope that the tourism will revive very soon. Of course, there is always light after the dark, i.e. “Rays of Hope.” No doubt, Pokhara is equipped with all amenities for adventure and holiday lovers. But still it is lacking with some important infrastructures like, Pokhara International Airport, Pokhara Bus Park,Walking trail around the Fewa lake, Expansion of high way road to Kathmandu, Sunauli and Corrala border( China ) and most importantly National Carrier should be strengthen which certainly can support to boost the tourism in Pokhara and the country. On behalf of Pokhara Tourism Council, I would like to express my thanks to International Labour Organization (ILO) and ILO Japan for their support for LED Project (Local Economic Development). We expect that this website will definitely help to enhance the tourism by providing reliable and constructive information about Pokhara and the region and also promote tourism awareness among the people and its professionals.
    Thank you

   \n\nSom Thapa
   \n\nPresident
    \n\nPokhara Tourism Council
</string>
    <string name="pep">
        \n\nPokhara Tourism Council (PTC) is a nonprofit making organization representing the tourism industry of Pokhara in Western Nepal. It was established in July 1995 as a Pokhara Toursim Promotion Committee and in 2002, officially established in the name of Pokhara Tourism Council with the major objective of playing role of coordinator to promote and develop tourism industry in Pokhara in an organized way.

\n\nIt Also plays a vital role to coordinate with all the stake holders for the development of tourism related infrastructures in Pokhara, providing suitable and reliable services to the tourists, promoting Pokhara both nationally and internationally, safeguarding the professional rights and interests of tourism agencies and making best efforts to keep the natural environment of Pokhara as neat, clean and healthy.

\n\nAs an umbrella organization, it comprises of eleven major tourism and non tourism organizations as its members. These organizations include Pokhara Chamber of Commerce and Industry (PCCI), Paschimanchal Hotel Association Pokhara (PHAP), Trekking Agencies’ Association of Nepal (TAAN) Western Regional Association, Pokhara, Nepal Association of Tour and Travel Agents (NATTA) Regional Association Pokhara, Restaurant and Bar Association of Nepal (REBAN)- Pokhara Chapter, Taxi Entrepreneurs Association Pokhara, Pokhara Bus Entrepreneurs Association, Trekking Equipment Shops Association (TESA) Pokhara, Embroidery and Garment Association (EGA) Pokhara, Nepal Air Sports Association (NAA) and  Ganesh Laxmi Charitable (GLC) Trust Pokhara.

\n\nDevelopment of eco tourism, responsible tourism and tourism related human resources through various capacity building activities (e.g. trainings, exposure visits, seminars, etc.) are the key thrusts of PTC. On behalf of all the member associations, PTC co-ordinates with Nepal Government, foreign agencies, tourism associations, local governmental bodies and other stakeholders. It also acts as one of the pressure groups to provide visionary suggestions and valuable ideas to the government to assist in formulating sound plans and policies for the sustainable and eco- friendly development of tourism in Pokhara.
    </string>


</resources>
